The Central Research Institute's 1st January knowledge lecture will begin.
中央研究所の1月知識講座が始まります。
Let's welcome Director Peng Xun-ning, the vice president, to join us.
副社長の彭訓寧所長の参加を歓迎しましょう。
Good evening, everyone.
皆さん、こんばんわ。
I am very happy to welcome the special professor of the Taiwan National University, Dr. Li Bingshan.
台湾国立大学の特別教授、李冰山博士をお迎えできることを大変うれしく思います。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
He is also a member of the Academia Sinica
彼は中央研究院の会員でもあります。
Around 1991 to 1997
1991年から1997年頃
He used to be the director of our information office
彼はかつて私たちの情報局の所長でした
And now go back to National Taiwan University
そして今度は国立台湾大学に戻ります
Today he... I send it back to my mother's house
今日彼は...母の家に送り返します
He's also happy to be back at his mother's house
彼も母親の家に戻ることができて嬉しかったです
Today is of course offering a very new woman
もちろん今日は非常に新しい女性を提供しています
look at so many people
たくさんの人を見てください
I know there are seats in front
前に席があるのはわかっています
There are still seats in front of you. You're welcome.
あなたの前の席はまだございますので、どうぞ。
ok my...
私の[OK...
Just give a brief introduction to Professor Li Linshan
リー・リンシャン教授について簡単に紹介します。
Although everyone has
誰もが持っているのに、
Professor Li Linshan
李林山教授
Graduated from the Department of Electrical Engineering, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学電気工学科卒業
Later to Stanford University in the United States
その後アメリカのスタンフォード大学へ
get a Ph.D.
博士号を取得する
1979 very early
1979 年のかなり早い時期
started teaching at National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学で教鞭をとり始める
He used to be the Director of Qi in the Information Department of National Taiwan University
彼はかつて国立台湾大学情報学部のチー部長を務めていました。
As I just said, the director of the Institute of Information, Academia Sinica
先ほども言いましたが、中央研究院情報研究所の所長は、
Chairman of National Taiwan University Research and Development Association
国立台湾大学研究開発協会会長
Dean of School of Electronics, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学電子学部長
Dr. Doge and his work in the United States
ドージ博士と米国における彼の研究
area of ​​expertise at the time was
当時の専門分野は
satellite communication
衛星通信
When returning to China in 1979
1979年に中国に帰国したとき
Research resources at that time
当時の研究資料
still lacking
まだ足りない
Then he decided to find a
それから彼は、
with minimum cost
最小限のコストで
most common equipment
最も一般的な機器
possible research directions
考えられる研究の方向性
and start by reading a textbook
そして教科書を読むことから始めてください
Try doing voice technology research
音声技術の研究をしてみよう
first in 1984
1984年に初めて
developed
発展した
Chinese Speech Synthesis Technology
中国語音声合成技術
And completed the first edition of Great Wisdom in 1991
そして1991年に『Great Wisdom』の初版が完成しました。
Chinese Speech Recognition Technology
中国語音声認識技術
Let the Chinese computer can speak
中国語のコンピュータに話せるようにしましょう
Chinese Listening to Chinese
中国語 中国語を聞く
he in 1992
1992年の彼
For Chinese computer
中華パソコンの場合
Contributions to input technology
入力技術への貢献
Elected as IEEE Fellow
IEEEフェローに選出
It is the fourth IEEE Fellow in Taiwan
台湾では 4 人目の IEEE フェローです
I still remember 1994
1994年のことを今でも覚えています
When Dean Li returned to Taiwan
ディーン・リーが台湾に帰国したとき
I will accompany Dean Li to the information center
ディーン・リーに同行してインフォメーションセンターへ行きます
As a result, Director Li Linshan showed off his Spirit No. 1
その結果、リー・リンシャン監督はスピリットNo.1を披露した。
With his self-certified gun yuan's recitative input voice
自称銃元の朗読入力音声で
Then display the voice in the computer
次に音声をコンピュータに表示します
At that time the input was
その時の入力は、
Because his self-certification gun element is recitative
彼の自己認証銃要素はレシタティーヴォなので
So it works great
だからそれはうまくいきます
I'm still very impressed
今でもとても感動しています
Then he also said that the computer can focus
それから彼は、コンピュータは集中できるとも言いました。
After a person with an accent like me gets burnt
私のような訛りのある人間が火傷を負った後
He can recognize my accent
彼は私のなまりを認識できる
very impressed
非常に感動
Then in 2010 with Chinese voice technology
そして 2010 年に中国の音声技術を導入
and contributions to voice information search technology
音声情報検索技術への貢献
Elected ISDA Fellow of the International Phonetic Association
国際音声協会の ISDA フェローに選出
At that time, there were only about 30 ISDA Fellows in the world
当時、ISDAフェローは世界で約30人しかいなかった
including many linguists
多くの言語学者を含む
those three asians
あの三人のアジア人
he is one of three asians
彼は3人のアジア人のうちの1人です
Of course in Taiwan in 1993
もちろん1993年の台湾で
Academic Award from the Ministry of Education
文部科学省学術賞を受賞
Received a National Award from the Ministry of Education in 2004
2004年に文部科学大臣賞を受賞
So I'm very focused on doing research all the way.
だから私はずっと研究に集中しています。
Also did a lot of academic administrative services
学術行政サービスも数多く行った
shall we applaud
拍手しましょうか
Welcome to Li Pingshan Newspaper Office
李屏山新聞社へようこそ
Do you hear my voice? Hear it
私の声が聞こえますか？
OK, thank you Vice President Peng
OK、ペン副大統領、ありがとう
Then I am very glad to have this opportunity to come back to Academia Sinica
そして、中央研究院に戻ってくるこの機会を得て、とてもうれしく思います。
As he said, it's like going back to her mother's house
彼が言ったように、母親の家に帰ったようなものです
then i remember when i was here
それから私はここにいたときのことを思い出します
There was a beautiful time more than ten years ago
10年以上前には素晴らしい時代がありました
Then every plant and tree in Academia Sinica, bit by bit
それから中央研究院のすべての草木が少しずつ
Lili is still in my heart, Xu Xurusheng
リリは今でも私の心の中にいます、徐雪生
I think Academia Sinica can be regarded as eternal
中央研究院は永遠と言えると思います
On the one hand, it is also a day and a month
一方で、それは日でもあり、月でもあります。
it's nice to be back here
ここに戻ってこられて嬉しいです
Thank you all for coming to today's speech
今日の講演にお越しいただいた皆様、ありがとうございました
Ok, so it's the first time I've seen such an advanced pointer
そうですね、これほど高度なポインターを見たのは初めてです
ok so let me try to use it
わかったので使ってみます
I think it might be better if I use this so I don't have to face the computer
これを使えばパソコンに向かなくて済むので良いかも知れません
No, I haven't used it, so let me try using
いや、使ったことないので使ってみます
Everyone can take a look
誰でも見ることができます
today's speech topic
今日のスピーチのテーマ
I know everyone
私はみんなを知っています
This sesame open the door
このゴマが扉を開ける
but you also
でもあなたも
sorry i just can't use it
ごめんなさい、使えないだけです
but you know me
でもあなたは私を知っています
not talking about the Arabian Nights
アラビアンナイトの話ではない
Not talking about Alibaba
アリババの話ではない
I'm talking about the gates to treasures of knowledge
私が話しているのは知識の宝への扉についてです
OK I'm talking about the door to the treasure trove of knowledge
はい、知識の宝庫への扉について話しています。
So today's speech is mainly
それで今日のスピーチは主に
these parts
これらの部品
then i will start by explaining
それでは説明から始めます
Speech signal and its analysis
音声信号とその解析
and then i will
それから私はそうします
this
これ
Explain how speech recognition works
音声認識の仕組みを説明する
Then enter today's topic
それでは今日のトピックに入ります
is the search for audio information
音声情報の検索です
and finally
そして最後に
before the end
終わりの前に
i will start by saying
私は言うことから始めます
and finally
そして最後に
before the end
終わりの前に
I'll show you a few live demonstrations
いくつかのライブデモンストレーションをお見せします
Then I will divide this general knowledge
それでは、この一般知識を分けていきます
professional knowledge
専門知識
and the three levels of language learning
言語学習の 3 つのレベル
come to show everyone
来てみんなに見せてください
everybody look
みんな見て
I feel like this one moves more than I thought
思った以上に動く気がする
Then maybe I'll use this
じゃあこれを使おうかな
This step back a bit, I still use
これは少し後退しましたが、私はまだ使用しています
I'd better use this
これを使ったほうがいいですよ
get used to it
それに慣れる
ok then let's start
はい、それでは始めましょう
Everyone knows what I'm talking about today
今日私が何を話しているのかは誰もが知っています
then we understand that the network
ネットワークが
It is already our daily life today
それはもう私たちの日常です
an indispensable part
欠かせない部分
All kinds of things are online
あらゆるものがオンラインに
Then it's especially worth talking about
それなら特に話す価値がある
It should mean that we all understand
それは私たち全員が理解していることを意味するはずです
像Google, Amazon, Facebook, YouTube
像Google, Amazon, Facebook, YouTube
These things provide our daily life
これらは私たちの日常生活を支えています
a lot of information
多くの情報
The other thing we can say is
もう一つ言えることは、
Knowledge Warranty as we know it in the past
これまでに知られている知識保証
Like a library or a museum, etc.
図書館や美術館など。
It has been gradually virtualized or demonstrated
徐々に仮想化または実証されてきました
We are doing research today and looking for a paper
私たちは今日調査を行っており、論文を探しています
Few people have to go to the library to find
図書館に行って探す必要がある人はほとんどいません
Because we found it on the Internet
ネットで見つけたので
Similarly, online courses, distance learning, e-books, these
同様に、オンラインコース、遠隔教育、電子書籍、これら
It has also become the most efficient learning tool.
また、最も効率的な学習ツールにもなりました。
in this situation
この状況では
We can understand the only commonality of human beings today
今日私たちが理解できる人類の唯一の共通点
Is Safeguarding Where Online?
保護はオンラインで行われますか?
if you think so
あなたがそう思うならば
All knowledge becomes digital content
あらゆる知識がデジタルコンテンツになる
What is the most attractive form of digital content at this time?
現時点で最も魅力的なデジタルコンテンツとは何でしょうか？
We immediately thought of audio-visual multimedia
私たちはすぐにオーディオビジュアルマルチメディアを思いつきました
The reason we will understand immediately
すぐにわかる理由
Because of multimedia it can be colorful
マルチメディアだからカラフルになれる
can be colorful
カラフルにすることができます
Then its biggest feature is that it can be written without text
そして最大の特徴は文字なしで書けることです
But it can have voice narration
ただし音声ナレーションも可能
The speech we speak is the sound signal of human language
私たちが話す音声は人間の言語の音声信号です
then our voice
それから私たちの声
From this point of view
この観点から見ると
we will understand
私たちは理解します
Multimedia as long as it comes with voice narration
音声ナレーション付きのマルチメディア
Usually it can describe digital content
通常、デジタルコンテンツを記述することができます
theme concept
主題概念
For example
例えば
when i listen to tv news
テレビのニュースを聞いているとき
i can close my eyes
目を閉じてもいいです
just listen to him
彼の話を聞いてください
I already know the news he's talking about
彼が話しているニュースはもう知っています
I don't need to actually watch his picture
実際に彼の写真を見る必要はない
Of course you can watch
もちろん視聴も可能です
but i can ignore it
でも無視してもいいよ
This means
これの意味は
The voice has been very clearly described
声がとてもわかりやすく描写されています
his multimedia content
彼のマルチメディアコンテンツ
so I can use it for digital content searches
デジタル コンテンツの検索に使用できるようにする
On the other hand we also understand
その一方で、私たちも理解しています
Today's Web Searches
今日のウェブ検索
still text-based
まだテキストベース
Just like you enter a text when surfing the Internet
インターネットサーフィン時にテキストを入力するのと同じように
He is doing text comparison
彼はテキスト比較を行っています
So even if you're looking for a YouTube video
YouTube で動画を探している場合でも
we will find him
私たちは彼を見つけます
Also because of whoever uploaded that video
その動画をアップロードした人のせいでもあります
while he is uploading
彼がアップロードしている間
he wrote a bunch of words
彼はたくさんの言葉を書きました
Then we were looking for him based on text
それから私たちはテキストに基づいて彼を探しました
This shows that today this part still has a very large space
これは、現在でもこの部分に非常に大きなスペースがあることを示しています。
not yet developed
まだ開発されていない
Because on the one hand we also understand smartphones and devices
一方で私たちはスマートフォンやデバイスについても理解しているので、
Other possible Internet tools
その他の可能なインターネット ツール
what's there
そこには何がありますか
we'll find out
私たちはそれを見つけます
For example, there can be various electronic devices in the car
たとえば、車内にはさまざまな電子機器が搭載されています。
At home, such as the living room and kitchen
リビングやキッチンなどご家庭で
Can have various home appliances
さまざまな家電を設置できる
There are also various accessories
付属品も色々あります
e.g. glasses, watches
例：メガネ、時計
These may become the tools we use to surf the Internet
これらは私たちがインターネットをサーフィンするために使用するツールになるかもしれません
Common features of these things
こういったものに共通する特徴は、
yes they can let us anytime, anywhere
はい、いつでもどこでもさせてもらえます
Connect with global knowledge and information
世界中の知識や情報とつながる
They also have a great feature
素晴らしい機能もあります
It's thin, short, and ubiquitous
細くて短くてどこにでもある
can enter our daily life
私たちの日常生活に入り込むことができます
use anytime, anywhere
いつでもどこでも使える
i.e. personal computer
つまりパーソナルコンピュータ
are no longer everyday information users
もはや日常的な情報ユーザーではありません
the only darling
唯一の最愛の人
And this we found
そして、私たちが見つけたのがこれです
under this environment
この環境下では
What is the most convenient interface for surfing the Internet?
インターネットサーフィンに最も便利なインターフェースは何ですか?
at least voice is one of them
少なくとも音声はその1つです
Why voice is one of them
なぜ音声もその一つなのでしょうか?
at least the first
少なくとも最初の
because it's just us talking
それは私たちだけが話しているからです
we can talk anytime anywhere
いつでもどこでも話せます
So you can use it anytime, anywhere
いつでもどこでも使えるので、
Any of these tools we can talk to him
これらのツールのどれでも私たちは彼と話すことができます
So any tool can be used
なのでどんなツールでも使える
Talking is the most convenient and natural
話すのが一番便利で自然です
Another point is that the voice is the most special
もう一つのポイントは、声が最も特別であるということです
that is, it can be said in place
つまり、その場で言えます
what is a sentence in place
文は何ですか
Let's say I'm looking for the US presidential election
米国大統領選挙を探しているとしましょう
I'd say the US presidential election is already in place
アメリカ大統領選挙はもう始まっていると言いました
Any touch other than voice
声以外のタッチ
It is impossible to press a button in one sentence
ボタンを一言で押すことは不可能です
So Voice Has Its Benefits
音声には利点がある
So you can imagine
それで想像できます
what am i talking about here
私はここで何を話しているのですか
This is our future online world
これが私たちの未来のオンライン世界です
or today's online world
あるいは今日のオンライン世界
in our digital content
当社のデジタルコンテンツでは
or knowledge
または知識
there are a bunch of text
大量のテキストがあります
There are a bunch of multimedia
マルチメディアがたくさんある
this will be more and more
これはますます多くなるだろう
then we can still search with today's text
その後も今日のテキストで検索できます
go find these things
これらのものを探しに行ってください
as long as it has words written on it
言葉が書かれている限り
But we can also search directly by voice
ただし、音声で直接検索することもできます
At this time, I can directly use
現時点では、直接使用できます
this smart phone
このスマートフォン
or similar handheld interface
または同様のハンドヘルドインターフェイス
Then I go directly to voice with voice
それから私は声で声に直接行きます
I can find his things based on the content of his voice
彼の声の内容から彼の持ち物を見つけることができます
If I find the text
テキストを見つけたら
I can also use listening to ask him to synthesize it for me, etc.
リスニングを使って合成してもらうこともできます。
that's what we're going to talk about today
それが今日私たちが話すことです
In other words, although today's Internet interface is this
つまり、今日のインターネットインターフェイスはこれですが、
It's text, you go find the text
それはテキストです、テキストを探しに行ってください
But everything that can be done with words can be done with voice
しかし、言葉でできることはすべて音声でできる
So we would expect that it should be possible to do these things with voice
したがって、これらのことを音声で実行できるはずだと期待します。
Of course, we also know that there are many interactions on the Internet today.
もちろん、今日インターネット上で多くのやり取りが行われていることも承知しています。
which means we lost something
それは私たちが何かを失ったことを意味します
net give me something
ネット、何か下さい
have some interaction
何らかの交流を持つ
This interaction is a dialogue of sound in terms of Silver
このインタラクションは、シルバーの観点から言えば音の対話です。
That can go a step further and be multimodal
それはさらに一歩進んで、マルチモーダルになる可能性があります
Which means I might still be using touch
つまり、まだタッチを使用している可能性があります
There are also some keys
鍵もいくつかあります
then become a multimodal conversation
その後、マルチモーダルな会話になります
That's what we're going to talk about today
今日はそれについて話します
That is, we can use voice commands
つまり、音声コマンドを使用できます
through hand-held electronic devices
手持ちの電子機器を通じて
Then on the one hand, with the help of multimedia digital content
一方では、マルチメディアデジタルコンテンツの助けを借りて
All with some voice narration to browse and search for information using the web
Web を使用して情報を閲覧および検索するための音声ナレーションがすべて含まれています
In a simple sentence
簡単な文で
This means that what we are talking about is the voice version of Google-related technologies
これは、私たちが話しているのは、Google 関連テクノロジーの音声バージョンであることを意味します。
That gets in simpler terms
もっと簡単に言うと
It's voice unlimited Internet access
音声無制限のインターネットアクセスです
that's what i'm going to talk about today
それが今日私が話すことです
ok so how about the beginning
さて、それでは始めはどうですか
Let's show you first
まずはお見せしましょう
What does the sound signal look like
音声信号はどのようなものですか
how we analyze it
それをどのように分析するか
Everyone knows that sound is sound waves in the air
音が空気中の音波であることは誰もが知っています
we can use a microphone
私たちはマイクを使うことができます
turn it into an electrical signal
それを電気信号に変える
The signal of electricity is the cold and heat of a time
電気の信号は時の寒さと暑さ
like this
このような
This time we go further
今度はさらに進んでいきます
Convert the electrical signal into a pile of hours and enter it into the computer
電気信号を時間の山に変換し、コンピューターに入力します。
For example
例えば
This short signal is actually a point
この短い信号が実はポイントなのです
one point
ワンポイント
Then I will turn these points into hours
次に、これらのポイントを時間に換算します
The computer can handle the time
コンピュータは時間を処理できる
This is what we call a voice signal
これが音声信号と呼ばれるものです
what does it look like
それは何に見えますか
us
私たち
Let's look at a few examples
いくつかの例を見てみましょう
For example, this is an example of some vowels
たとえば、これはいくつかの母音の例です。
You can see, for example, this is E
たとえば、これは E であることがわかります。
this is R etc.
Rなどです。
You immediately find that it has a common characteristic
共通の特徴があることがすぐにわかります
That is, they are all cyclical
つまり、それらはすべて周期的です
Then this cycle is the so-called pitch
このサイクルがいわゆるピッチです
Jizhou
冀州
Jizhou said it has a very clear physical meaning
冀州氏は、これには非常に明確な物理的意味があると述べた
is its inverse
その逆です
It is what we call F0
それがF0と呼ばれるものです
is the pitch that our ears hear
私たちの耳に聞こえる音程です
So the immediate thing that comes to mind is
そこですぐに思い浮かぶのは、
our four voices
私たちの4つの声
You guys know our fourth sound like R
皆さんは私たちの4番目の音「R」を知っていますか？
This pitch is slowly falling
このピッチはゆっくりと下がっていく
As time goes on
時間が経つにつれて
The horizontal axis is time
横軸は時間です
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
I'm the one who posted the music R
音楽Rを投稿したのは私です
its cycle
そのサイクル
move forward
前進する
It cycle becomes bigger and bigger
そのサイクルはどんどん大きくなっていきます
So the pitch gets lower and lower
それでピッチはどんどん低くなっていきます
Then it becomes R
そうするとRになります
if i pronounce
私が発音したら
This cycle is getting shorter and shorter
このサイクルはどんどん短くなっていきます
getting shorter
短くなる
it climbs up
それは登る
that's the second sound wait
それは2番目の音です待ってください
We call this voice Joy in Voice
私たちはこの声を Joy in Voice と呼んでいます
There are many purple sounds that look like this
このような紫色の音がたくさんあります
this is a purple sound
これは紫の音です
sandwiched between two periodic vowels
2つの周期母音に挟まれている
It has no cycles at all and is like a bunch of noise
サイクルがまったくなく、ノイズの塊のようです
We call it Qingyin unvoiced
私たちはそれを無声清音と呼びます
Of course Ziyin is not exactly Qingyin
もちろん、Ziyinは正確にはQingyinではありません
There are also like this purple tone is v
こんな紫色もありますよv
It is also sandwiched between two periodic vowels
また、2つの周期母音の間に挟まれています
But it's also clearly cyclical
しかし、それは明らかに周期的でもあります
Like this Violet v it's still scorching
このヴァイオレットみたいにv まだ灼熱だよ
if you understand this
これを理解していれば
Let's look at the signal length of a sentence
文の信号の長さを見てみましょう
like this
このような
this is a sentence
これは文です
Our total length is 0.1 seconds
私たちの全長は0.1秒です
Then there are a total of eight segments of 0.8 seconds
次に、0.8 秒のセグメントが合計 8 つあります。
This sentence is should we chase
この文は追いかけるべきです
you will see the first
最初に見るでしょう
This is Qingyin
こちらは清音です
it's out of cycle
サイクルが外れています
this is un
これは国連です
It is clear that there is a cycle, etc.
周期などがあることが分かります。
This is a light tone, there is no period
これは明るいトーンです、ピリオドはありません
This A is clearly periodic, etc.
この A は明らかに周期的です。
That's our signal
それが私たちの言うことです
How do we analyze such a signal
このような信号をどのように分析するか
Of course, there are many ways to analyze
もちろん分析方法はたくさんありますが、
However, one of the most basic methods of analyzing signals
ただし、信号を分析する最も基本的な方法の 1 つは、
is to analyze its frequency
その周波数を分析することです
Then analyze the frequency
次に周波数を分析します
then the simplest idea
次に、最も単純なアイデア
I think it can be explained like this
このように説明できると思います
It seems that in the phasor of the three-dimensional space that we are very familiar with
私たちがよく知っている三次元空間のフェーザーの中にあるようです。
A phasor I can use three mutually perpendicular bases
フェーザー I は 3 つの相互に垂直な基底を使用できます
Ijk spread it out
Ijkがそれを広めた
The three phasors
3 つのフェーザー
Each of the three perpendicular bases has a component
3 つの垂直な底辺にはそれぞれコンポーネントがあります。
is the ADC
ADCです
So I can write like this
だからこんな風に書ける
Of course, these three bases don't have to be like that.
もちろん、この 3 つの拠点はそのようにする必要はありません。
we can move it
私たちはそれを動かすことができます
like turn it around
ひっくり返すような
if a turn
順番が回れば
This Ijk is converted into iProng JProng KProng
この Ijk は iProng JProng KProng に変換されます
when i turn like this
私がこうなったら
My weight has also changed
体重も変わりました
Although my phasor
私のフェイザーですが
is the same as A
Aと同じです
Then such a conversion relationship
すると、このような変換関係が
In fact, we analyze the frequency
実際に周波数を分析してみると、
this
これ
This Fuji conversion is exactly the same thing
このフジコンバートも全く同じことです
It's just a sign we're thinking now
それは私たちが今考えている単なる兆候です
is very big
とても大きいです
it spreads out across the timeline
それはタイムライン全体に広がります
Therefore
したがって
it's on this T1T2T3
このT1T2T3にあります
have these values
これらの価値観を持っています
as if on these bases
あたかもこれらの基盤の上にあるかのように
There are these components that are the same
同じコンポーネントがあります
So why?
なぜ？
When we do a Fuji conversion
富士コンバートを行う場合
expand this signal to
この信号を次のように展開します
When this frequency goes up
この周波数が上がると
I'm on every now
今はずっとオンです
This converts every
これはすべてを変換します
every point becomes a frequency
あらゆる点が周波数になる
In other words, a cos has different frequencies
言い換えれば、cos には異なる周波数があります。
Then there are these values
次に、これらの値があります
that means like
それは次のような意味です
I call it these
私はそれをこれらと呼んでいます
After turning these bases around
これらの拠点をひっくり返した後、
I regain the weight
体重が元に戻ってしまう
So what this says above is
したがって、上で言っていることは、
in this signal
この信号で
components of each frequency
各周波数の成分
how much each
それぞれいくら
Then we call this frequency
次に、この周波数を周波数と呼びます
relatively
比較的
this one just now
これは今のやつ
is the so-called real
いわゆる本物です
With this understanding
この理解のもとに
let's go back now
今戻りましょう
I want to analyze the sentence just now
今の文章を分析したい
what to do
何をすべきか
you can imagine my signal
私の信号を想像できるでしょう
always changing
常に変化する
For example, here is
たとえば、ここにあります
looks like this
このように見えます
here is
ここは
A looks like this
Aはこんな感じ
how do i analyze it
どうやって分析すればいいですか
I have to analyze it piece by piece
一つ一つ分析しなければならない
I can analyze this short paragraph
この短い段落を分析できます
this frequency
この周波数
frequency of A etc.
Aの頻度など
So what we can do
では、私たちにできることは何か
just put this signal
この信号を入れてください
Take a small piece and a small piece to do it separately
小さな部分と小さな部分を別々に取ってください
Fuji conversion
富士変換
Each converted result
それぞれの変換結果
I draw it as a line
線として描きます
use its black and white or color
白黒またはカラーを使用する
to show its height
その高さを示すために
as if it was like this one by one
一つ一つこうだったかのように
because every conversion
なぜなら、すべての変換が
Actually it's like this
実はこんな感じです
graph at this frequency
この周波数でのグラフ
then i am actually
じゃあ私は実は
A lot of these pictures are lined up here
こんな写真がたくさん並んでいます
I just use the color for its height
高さのために色を使用しているだけです
or in black and white
または白黒で
become like this
こうなる
that kind of
そのようなもの
Two-dimensional graph becomes a two-dimensional graph
2次元グラフが2次元グラフになる
This horizontal axis is the original time
この横軸は本来の時間です
same time as this time
今回と同じ時間
and the vertical axis becomes frequency
縦軸は周波数になります
So it is a two-dimensional graph
つまり二次元グラフです
We call it spectrogram
それをスペクトログラムと呼びます
maybe a food chart
たぶん食事表
we can give an example
例を挙げることができます
use just right
ちょうどよく使う
There's one more thing
もう一つあります
there's some really high places on this
この上にはかなり高い場所がいくつかある
The components of these frequencies are particularly large
これらの周波数の成分は特に大きい
These are the times when we speak
私たちが話すのはこんな時です
inside our mouth
私たちの口の中
some frequencies of vocal resonance
声の共鳴のいくつかの周波数
after having this
これを持った後
Let's look back at that sentence now
今その文を振り返ってみましょう
that sentence
その文
we just said
私たちは今言いました
This is the total sentence from the beginning to the end
これは最初から最後までの全文です
Then each segment is 0.1 seconds
したがって、各セグメントは 0.1 秒です
I'm redrawing it now
今描き直してます
put this horizontal axis
この横軸を置きます
compress it into a paragraph
段落に圧縮する
from here to here
ここからここまで
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
So this sentence is still should we chase
したがって、この文はまだ追いかけるべきです
But I'll pull up the heavy shaft first
でもまずは重軸を引き上げる
So the picture just now becomes here
ということで今の写真がこちらになります
So this is the signal on the timeline
これがタイムライン上の信号です
just an axis flag
ただの軸フラグ
Between the two lines is an axis flag.
2 つの線の間には軸フラグがあります。
It's packed into a pile.
山盛りに詰め込まれています。
I draw the same timeline here
同じタイムラインをここに描きます
The upper axis is my frequency
上軸は私の周波数です
The picture above is my time spectrum
上の写真は私の時間スペクトルです
we can see
見える
For example, this is
たとえば、これは
Its time signal looks like this
時報はこんな感じです
Its frequency is like this
その頻度はこんな感じです
this is a thing
これは物です
things like this
このようなもの
it has axis flags
軸フラグがあります
Here things just become like this and so on
ここでは物事はこのようになります、など
This is what we use time spectrum to analyze
これは時間スペクトルを使用して分析するものです
What about another step?
もう一歩はどうでしょうか？
we just said
私たちは今言いました
the top of these parts
この部分の上部
is the resonance frequency
は共振周波数です
is that each point has a value
各点には値があるということです
then i can connect it
それなら接続できます
this is an area
ここはエリアです
If I draw this
これを描いたら
just this example
この例だけ
you can see
見ることができます
This is another word
これは別の言葉です
but
しかし
Below mine is the signal on its timeline
私のものの下にはタイムライン上の信号があります
Above is its time spectrum
上はその時間スペクトルです
Then I can actually take these four resonant frequencies
次に、これら 4 つの共振周波数を実際に取得します。
Draw four curves
4つの曲線を描く
Then we can see that at these frequencies
次に、これらの周波数で次のことがわかります。
is the resonance frequency
は共振周波数です
And it with each tone of time
そしてそれは時間のトーンごとに
this sentence is this sentence
この文はこの文です
The resonant frequency of each sound is changing
それぞれの音の共鳴周波数が変化する
Okay, what I just told you is
さて、私が今言ったことは、
voice on paper
紙に書かれた声
Below we show you a real voice
以下、実際の声をご紹介します
this is a sentence
これは文です
we can first hear what it is
まずはそれが何であるかを聞くことができます
This bus does not arrive at National Taiwan University
このバスは国立台湾大学には到着しません
That's what's underneath
それが下にあるものです
The bottom piece is what we just saw
一番下の部分は今見たものです
signal unfolded in time
時間の経過とともに展開される信号
That piece in the middle is what we just saw
真ん中の部分が今見たものです
food recipes
食品譜
we see every note of it
私たちはそのすべての音符を見ます
what it looks like in frequency
周波数的にはどのように見えるか
What about the distribution of its different frequencies
異なる周波数の分布はどうなるでしょうか
Then these four four color curves
次に、これら 4 つの 4 つのカラー カーブ
is its four resonant frequencies
はその 4 つの共振周波数です
that's up there
それはそこにあります
is the reciprocal of its period
はその周期の逆数です
that is pitch
それはピッチです
You see that this bus can't arrive
このバスは到着できないことがわかります
You can see that this is less than
これは以下であることがわかります
This is the fourth sound
これが4番目の音です
The second one will arrive more smoothly and so on.
2本目以降はさらにスムーズに届きます。
This is Taiwan, this is a university, etc.
ここは台湾、ここは大学など。
we can listen again
もう一度聞くことができます
This bus does not arrive at National Taiwan University
このバスは国立台湾大学には到着しません
We can also give an example
例を挙げることもできます
For example, let's see, for example, what is the sound here?
たとえば、ここでどんな音が出ているのか見てみましょう。
and
と
about sound
約的音
if here to here
ここからここまでなら
The next thing is to learn
次は学ぶことです
you know what it is from here to here
ここからここまでが何であるか知っていますか
Taiwan
台湾
OK
OK
What I want to show you is this Tao
見せたいのはこのタオ
It doesn't look like this way
このようには見えません
Because of the call behind this
この背後にある呼び出しのため
so it's already you heard it's going to dial
それで、ダイヤルすることはすでに聞いています
What about this way?
この方法はどうでしょうか？
What if you look inside
中を見てみるとどうなるか
kind of like
みたいな
Looking at its spectrum, it looks a bit like
スペクトルを見ると、少し似ています。
You can see that the pitch is also much different
ピッチもかなり違うのがわかります
What about this description?
この説明はどうでしょうか？
even in the same sentence
同じ文の中でも
The same person speaks two identical sounds
同じ人が 2 つの同じ音を話します
is very different
とても違う
we can pull it out a bit
少し引き出すことができます
for example
例えば
this is less than
これは未満です
What if I pull it out to a certain extent?
ある程度抜いたらどうなるでしょうか？
you can see its cycle
そのサイクルがわかります
This cycle is very clear
このサイクルは非常に明確です
Then there is a lot of difference between the two before and after.
すると、前後の2つには大きな違いがあります。
etc.
等
good
良い
The above passage is for you to understand
上記の一節はあなたが理解できるようにするためのものです
what sound do we see
私たちはどんな音を見ますか
good
良い
What I want to tell you next is
次にお伝えしたいのは、
How do we let machines recognize human voices
どうやって機械に人間の声を認識させるのか
then we immediately
それなら私たちはそうします
The voice recognition that comes to mind on the Internet seems to be like this
インターネットで思いつく音声認識はこんな感じ
this is a sound
これは音です
today's weather is very good
今日の天気はとても良いです
For example, a short period of time is a lot of hours
たとえば、短い時間は長い時間になります。
I got these answers by general calculus
一般的な微積分によってこれらの答えが得られました
But the basement is not so easy
しかし、地下室はそう簡単ではありません
because you immediately understand
すぐに理解できるから
Each of our sounds has many phonetic characters
私たちのそれぞれの音には多くの表音文字が含まれています
Just based on what sounds these are
これらがどのような音であるかに基づいて、
You immediately think why this is not the gene of gold
なぜこれが金の遺伝子ではないのかすぐに考えます。
Why isn't this the day of the meal?
なぜこの日が食事の日ではないのですか？
Of course because we all know when we hear
もちろん、聞いたら誰もが知っているからです
why do people know
なぜ人々は知っているのか
because we know the context
私たちは文脈を知っているので
We also know these words in our heads
私たちも頭の中でこの言葉を知っています
So what a machine is going to do must also do these things
したがって、機械が行うことはこれらのことも行う必要があります
That is, we need to put all kinds of language knowledge into the computer.
つまり、あらゆる種類の言語知識をコンピューターに入力する必要があります。
At least one of these is a dictionary
これらのうち少なくとも 1 つは辞書です
one is grammar
一つは文法です
The dictionary told me that it is connected with this sound
辞書にはこの音と関係があると書いてありました
there is a word called today
今日という言葉があります
Grammar tells me that this word goes with this word
文法は、この単語はこの単語に当てはまると教えてくれます
can become a phrase etc.
フレーズなどになる可能性があります。
We humans actually know based on this
私たち人間は実際にこれに基づいて知っています。
this is not gold
これは金ではありません
this is not heaven
ここは天国ではない
The same computer has something like this
同じコンピュータには次のようなものがあります
Therefore we need to take this knowledge
したがって、この知識を取り入れる必要があります
integrated with these signals
これらの信号と統合される
that's what we're going to say
それが私たちが言おうとしていることです
how to do this
これを行う方法
So let's start with the basics
それでは基本から始めましょう
sound signal
音声信号
Divided into different patterns to see
パターンに分けて見る
For example
例えば
Let's say I want to recognize 10 sounds from 0 to 9
0から9までの10個の音を認識したいとします。
position sound comes in
ポジション音が入る
My first step is to take its features
私の最初のステップはその機能を理解することです
then the characteristic is
それなら特徴は
bunch of numbers
数字の束
wrap it up as a quantity
量としてまとめます
then follow the signal
それから信号に従ってください
I measure each item one by one
商品を一つ一つ採寸しております
become a line of items
アイテムの列になる
sequence of items
アイテムの順序
This sequence of items represents the sound
この一連の項目はサウンドを表します
Then I went to compare with the model
次にモデルと比較してみました
to make a decision
決断する
what is the model
モデルは何ですか
Then if we recognize 10 sounds from 0 to 9
次に、0から9までの10個の音を認識すると、
I want 10 models
10モデル欲しい
There is a model for each sound
それぞれの音にモデルがある
They were also trained on known sounds, respectively.
彼らはそれぞれ既知の音についても訓練を受けました。
So the spirit model has to tell him these things
したがって、霊モデルは彼にこれらのことを伝えなければなりません
These voices are spirit
この声は精霊だ
He uses their extracted feature sequence
彼は抽出された特徴シーケンスを使用します
To train the stored model
保存されているモデルをトレーニングするには
Then do this comparison
次に、この比較を行ってください
So here we have to explain
そこでここで説明しなければなりません
why feature
なぜ特徴があるのか
Once upon a time, my father, Sun Yuan, had a very good analogy
昔々、私の父、孫源は非常に優れた例え話をしていました。
He said I saw a man on the road
彼は道路で男を見たと言った
I want to judge whether he is a man or a woman
彼が男か女かを判断したい
I just look at his hair and his clothes
私はただ彼の髪と服を見ているだけです
89 ignore 10
89 無視 10
Occasionally make a mistake
時々間違いを犯す
That hair and clothes are characteristic
髪型と服装が特徴的ですね
if i take a photo
写真を撮ったら
Capture every bit of black and white
白黒をあらゆるビットで捉えます
then count
それから数えます
I can't tell if he's a man or a woman
彼が男なのか女なのかわかりません
But I knew it when I saw the clothes
でも服を見てわかった
the same reason
同じ理由
We want the feature to be the same
機能を同じにしておきたい
You see how complicated it was just taught
教えられたばかりのことがいかに複雑であるかがわかります
The same path looks completely different
同じ道でも全く違って見える
i can't rely on that
それは当てにならない
I want to grab features
特徴を掴みたい
So what is this characteristic?
では、この特徴は何でしょうか？
Let's take another example
別の例を見てみましょう
We are actually like what we just said
私たちは実際、今言ったことと同じです
the signal is here
信号はここにあります
Let me take this paragraph as an example, there are 512 points here
この段落を例に挙げてみましょう。ここには 512 個のポイントがあります
I do a calculation to get a series of numbers
一連の数値を取得するために計算を行います
Arrange it into an item called O1
O1というアイテムにアレンジ
I'll move this over later
これは後で移動します
Calculate these 512 points and get another item
この512ポイントを計算して別のアイテムをゲット
get these numbers too
これらの数字も取得してください
Get the second quantity called O2 O3 and so on
O2 O3 などという 2 番目の量を取得します。
The signal then becomes a row of terms
信号は用語の行になります
This is what we call the eigenvalue
これは固有値と呼ばれるものです
What's in it is not easy to explain here
何が入っているかをここで説明するのは簡単ではありません
but think of it this way
しかしこう考えてみてください
first we know
まず私たちは知っています
scientists have long understood
科学者たちは長い間理解していました
The human ear listens to the sound is to listen to the frequency
人間の耳は音を聞くということは周波数を聞くことです
And listen to the frequency
そして周波数を聞いてください
Then we do the same here
次に、ここでも同じことを行います
That is to capture the signal in each frequency band
それは各周波数帯域の信号を捉えることです
The second we also know
2番目は私たちも知っています
The sound we make is R or U or G or T
私たちが出す音は R または U または G または T
because of our accent
私たちのアクセントのせいで
different shape
違う形
So the pure-tooth relationship is very important
したがって、純粋な歯の関係は非常に重要です
In fact, we refer to these relations
実際、これらの関係について言及します。
only possible in these numbers
この数字でのみ可能です
So how big is this phasor?
では、このフェーザーの大きさはどれくらいでしょうか?
actually quite big
実際かなり大きい
Basically about 39 is about
基本的には約39です
is a very long, large phasor
非常に長くて大きなフェーザーです
Okay, with this understanding
さて、これを理解した上で
We probably know how these phasors come from
これらのフェーザーがどのようにして得られるかはおそらくわかっているでしょう。
So the next question is what are these models like?
それでは次の質問は、これらのモデルがどのようなものなのかということです。
then let's briefly explain
それでは簡単に説明しましょう
What is a model?
モデルとは何ですか?
There are many models today
今日はモデルがたくさんあります
But the most commonly used and generally successful
しかし、最も一般的に使用され、一般的に成功しているのは、
The so-called Hidden Markov Model
いわゆる隠れマルコフモデル
Headed Mark Model
頭付きマークモデル
Then let's explain this model in very simple language
それでは、このモデルを非常に簡単な言葉で説明しましょう
It is a series of states of sound
音の一連の状態です
string it up
紐を付けて
For example
例えば
If I want to recognize 10 sounds from 0 to 9
0から9までの10音を認識したい場合
Then 0 has a model of 0
すると 0 は 0 のモデルを持ちます
1 in 1 model
1in1モデル
For example
例えば
Assuming this is a model of 6
これが 6 のモデルであると仮定すると、
When I make the sound of 6
6の音を出すと
obviously
明らかに
The signal is preceded by a change of le
信号の前にファイルの変更が行われます。
middle may be e
真ん中はeかも知れません
may be followed by o
その後に o が続く場合があります
We tried the signal keeps changing
信号が変化し続けることを試してみました
From 6 to 6 state
6から6の状態へ
to describe the different sounds
さまざまな音を説明するには
what are these
これは何
These are the feature quantities we just mentioned.
これらは先ほど述べた特徴量です
You remember we have O1 O2 O3 here
ここに O1 O2 O3 があるのを覚えていますか
are my feature quantities
私の特徴量は
then you can imagine
それから想像してみてください
maybe my front
たぶん私の前
What about the three O12 O3?
O12 O3 の 3 つはどうですか?
is to describe the sound of this e
この e の音を説明するのは
Then 4567 may be the case of 2
そうすると 4567 は 2 の場合になるかもしれません
8 could be 3 and so on
8 は 3 などになる可能性があります
but you can understand right away
でもすぐに理解できるよ
It's okay when we send 6
6個送っても大丈夫ですよ
6 can also be 6
6は6にもなり得る
Can be long or short
可長可短
Each sound in the middle can be long or short
真ん中の各音は長くても短くても構いません
So actually you can imagine
それで実際には想像できます
Every state here
ここのすべての州
It can also be long or short
長くても短くてもいいです
So how to describe this phenomenon that can be long or short?
では、長くなる場合も短くなる場合もあるこの現象をどのように説明すればよいでしょうか?
Then we will use probability to illustrate it
次に、確率を使ってそれを説明します
So for example
たとえば
we will have
私たちは持っています
This means that if the previous O1 is in 1
これは、前の O1 が 1 にある場合を意味します。
The probability that the next O2 is still in 1
次の O2 がまだ 1 にある確率
And this is the O3 in front of me in 1
そしてこれが1の私の目の前にあるO3です
But the probability of the next O4 reaching 2, etc.
ただし、次の O4 が 2 に達する確率など。
what is this for
これは何のため
This is what we call the state transition probability
これは状態遷移確率と呼ばれるものです
In other words let's take for example
つまり、たとえば、
Suppose this is 0.1
これが 0.1 だと仮定します。
If this is 0.9
これが 0.9 であれば
I mean if I'm O3 it's 1
つまり、私が O3 なら 1 です
What about O4?
O4はどうですか？
9 Chengdu is 2
9 成都は 2
That is to say, I am in 1
つまり、私は1です
1 to 1 becomes 2
1対1が2になる
Because it pops up 90% of the time
90%の確率で現れるから
So 1 must be very short
したがって、1 は非常に短い必要があります
Conversely
逆に
if this is 0.9
これが 0.9 であれば
What if this is 0.1?
これが0.1だったらどうなるでしょうか？
that means say
つまり言う
What if O1 is 1
O1 が 1 の場合はどうなるでしょうか
Then O28 is still 1
そうするとO28は1のままです
90% or 1
90%または1
This is still 1
これはまだ 1 です
You can imagine that it takes about 9 times for 1 to become 2 and so on
1 が 2 になるまでに約 9 回かかることが想像できます。
tell me these odds
これらの確率を教えてください
How can they be long or short
どうして長くなったり短くなったりするのでしょうか
But these are just chances
しかし、これらは単なるチャンスです
not necessarily
必ずしも
they are all random
それらはすべてランダムです
can be changed
変更可能
they don't have a certain value
彼らは特定の価値を持っていません
on the other hand
一方で
Suppose I know that O1 is inside 1
O1 が 1 の中にあることがわかっているとします。
Do I know what the phasor length of O1 is?
O1 のフェーザー長はどれくらいか知っていますか?
i don't know
わからない
Let's take the inside of O1 just now
さっそくO1の内部を見てみましょう
For example, the X1 in O1
たとえば、O1 の X1
this is a value
これは価値です
what will happen to it
それはどうなりますか
What about the X1?
X1はどうでしょうか？
it can be like this
こんなこともあるよ
means that it can be this value
この値になる可能性があることを意味します
also this value
この値も
It will be all right
大丈夫ですよ
just the odds are different
確率が違うだけ
This is a probability distribution
これは確率分布です
In other words we completely
言い換えれば、私たちは完全に
Even if O1 is in 1
O1が1に入っていても
I have absolutely no idea how much the X1 will be
X1がいくらになるか全く分からない
i just let it
私はただそれをさせました
It has different values
さまざまな価値観があります
Both may be high or low
どちらも高い場合もあれば低い場合もあります
It's more likely to see this here
こちらのほうが見られる可能性が高いです
This chance is relatively small
このチャンスは比較的小さいです
that is it
それだ
what if it's in 2 or 3
2か3だったらどうしよう
also the same
また同じです
but each value can
しかし、それぞれの値は
The distribution of the probability of its value is just different
その値の確率の分布が違うだけです
This shows how diverse our signals are
これは私たちの信号がいかに多様であるかを示しています
very varied
非常に多様な
like you just saw
あなたが今見たように
same two to less than two to
同じ2～2未満～
it's just different
それは違うだけです
then in this case
それからこの場合は
in each state
それぞれの州で
Each value can have this many probability distributions
各値はこれだけの確率分布を持つことができます
what to do
何をすべきか
What we usually do is
私たちが普段やっているのは、
Approach it with a high wire probability
高いワイヤー確率でアプローチする
you may understand
あなたは理解できるかもしれません
Kose is a most standard probability model
コーセーは最も標準的な確率モデルです
We just give it an average
平均値を与えるだけです
with its fatness
その太さで
it has to be like that
そうでなければなりません
So no matter how long this
だから、いつまで経っても
I can even get close to it with a Kose
コーセーでもそれに近づけるよ
What about this way?
この方法はどうでしょうか？
I get a say 6
発言権は6
6 models
6モデル
There are a lot of parameters in this model
このモデルには多くのパラメータがあります
For example, these probabilities
たとえば、これらの確率は、
Gauss's and so on
ガウスなど
These parameters are all trainable
これらのパラメータはすべてトレーニング可能です
I just need to give the machine enough 666666
マシンに十分な量を与えるだけで十分です 666666
tell it it's 6 words
6単語だと言ってください
I can get all these papers of these 6 models
この6モデルの書類がすべて入手できます
when i have another voice called 6
6という別の声が出たとき
I throw its phasor in
私はそのフェーザーを投入します
can count its chances
そのチャンスを数えることはできる
The probability of 6 should be high and so on
6 の確率は高いはずです、など
This is the model we are talking about
これが私たちが話しているモデルです
Well, what I just said is limited to
さて、私が今言ったことはこれに限定されます
Suppose I recognize only 10 tones from 0 to 9
0 から 9 までの 10 音だけを認識するとします。
that is easier
その方が簡単です
What we really want to recognize is the continuous speech of great wisdom
私たちが本当に認識したいのは、偉大な知恵の継続的なスピーチです
What is the so-called great wisdom?
いわゆる大いなる知恵とは何でしょうか？
Do you know the commonly used words in Chinese?
中国語でよく使われる単語を知っていますか?
We can probably assume 60,000
おそらく60,000と想定できます
Then there are about 60,000 common words in English.
英語には一般的な単語が約 60,000 語あります。
So, in any of my random sounds
だから、私のランダムな音の中で
does it belong to a certain word
それは特定の単語に属しますか
It has 60,000
60,000ある
Then they talked consecutively
それから彼らは続けて話しました
In a word, you don't know it is
一言で言えば、あなたはそれを知らない
How many words are there in the middle?
真ん中の単語は何語ありますか？
I don't know where it's disconnected in the middle
途中で切れているのか分かりません
how do i deal with this problem
この問題にどう対処すればよいですか
you can imagine
想像できるでしょう
suppose my voice comes in
私の声が入ったとします
Like I just did it's feature
先ほどやったのと同じように、その機能
Phasor After getting a series of phasors
フェーザー 一連のフェーザーを取得した後
Suppose the voice is the sentence
音声が文章であると仮定します。
This is a speech
これはスピーチです
how can i tell it apart
どうやって見分けることができますか
The first point is that I try to find a way
最初のポイントは、方法を見つけようとすることです
since this is english
これは英語なので
I took all the possible basic sounds of English
英語の基本的な音をすべて取り込みました
find out
探し出す
There may be around 40 basic sounds in English
英語には約 40 個の基本音があると考えられます
So I took these basic notes
そこで私はこれらの基本的なメモを取りました
Create one for each basic tone
基本サウンドごとに 1 つ作成します
The model just mentioned
先ほど挙げたモデル
The model formed by these basic sounds
これらの基本音で形成されたモデル
is what we call an acoustic model
私たちが音響モデルと呼ぶものです
For example, in this sentence
たとえば、この文では
These are the basic sounds spelled out
これらは基本的な音の説明です
So therefore we want my acoustic model
したがって、私の音響モデルが必要です
can tell me
教えてください
In this sound are these basic tones
このサウンドにはこれらの基本音が含まれています
In fact, what we do is far more complicated than this
実際、私たちがやっていることはこれよりもはるかに複雑です
Because we found that the basic tone
基本的なトーンがわかったから
not just one model
1つのモデルだけではなく
as long as the front is different
フロントが違う限り
The back is different
背中が違う
it's just different
それは違うだけです
Did we just see that
それを見たばかりですか
The way ahead is different from the way behind
進む道と後ろの道は違う
because of that way
その方法のせいで
It will be different if there is one behind the front road.
前面道路の裏手にあれば別ですが。
So we actually want to see the difference between the front and the back
実際に表と裏の違いを見てみたいと思います
are different
異なっています
So we're using what's called a triple-sonic
そこで私たちはトリプルソニックと呼ばれるものを使用しています。
Tri-Fone
トライフォン
Suppose there are 40 basic sounds in English
英語には 40 個の基本音があるとします。
how many models do i need
モデルは何個必要ですか
40 to the third power so many kinds
40の3乗ってこんなに種類があるんだ
assuming i know the sounds
私が音を知っていると仮定して
This time I can use a dictionary
今度は辞書が使えます
The dictionary told me that the spelling of these sounds is this word
辞書は、これらの音の綴りがこの言葉であると教えてくれました
The spelling of these sounds is this word
これらの音の綴りはこの言葉です
etc.
等
so i can get the answer
それで答えを得ることができます
the answer is not
答えはそうではありません
We know that this world is inferior to consciousness ten to eighty-nine
この世界が意識10から89よりも劣っていることを私たちは知っています
why
なぜ
because you can immediately imagine
すぐに想像できるから
How similar is this sound to this sound
この音とこの音はどれくらい似ていますか
If we let our ears distinguish
耳で区別させれば
It's not easy to tell, right?
それを伝えるのは簡単ではありませんよね？
It is more difficult for machines to distinguish between
機械がこれらを区別するのはさらに困難です
So the machine can only tell me
だから機械は私に教えることしかできない
The sound is probably this
音はおそらくこれです
probably this
おそらくこれ
each with a score
それぞれにスコアが付いています
Then the highest score
じゃあ最高得点は
that's right
それは正しい
not necessarily
必ずしも
So after getting a bunch of tones
たくさんのトーンを取得した後
Can spell out many miraculous words
たくさんの奇跡の言葉を綴ることができます
then what should we do
じゃあどうすればいいのか
Then we need to have a
次に、
so-called language model
いわゆる言語モデル
he told me
彼は私に言った
In fact, only these three words together
実際には、この 3 つの単語が一緒になっているだけです
is the most smooth sentence
最も滑らかな文です
why
なぜ
he can count
彼は数えることができます
The word appears in
その言葉が登場するのは、
Chances of giant hands
巨大な手の可能性
then after the word
それからその言葉の後に
The probability of receiving this word
この言葉を受け取る確率は
then these two words
それからこの二つの言葉
The probability of following this word, etc.
この単語に続く確率など
multiply them all
それらをすべて掛け合わせます
is the probability of this sentence
この文の確率は
If the probability of the sentence is high
文の確率が高い場合
I feel like saying
と言いたくなる
This is relatively smooth
こちらは比較的スムーズです
So these are what we call language models
これらは言語モデルと呼ばれるものです
For example
例えば
This is the probability that two words are connected
これは 2 つの単語がつながる確率です
double grammar
二部文法
This is the probability of connecting three words
これは 3 つの単語がつながる確率です
the first two
最初の二つ
I will take this chance later
この機会を後で利用します
what we call triplicate grammars etc.
私たちが三重文法と呼ぶものなど。
What about these language models?
これらの言語モデルはどうでしょうか?
Of course how did it come about?
もちろん、それはどうやって生まれたのですか？
I can use a text database
テキストデータベースが使える
For example, if you go online, you can capture a database of 10 million words.
たとえば、オンラインに接続すると、1,000 万語のデータベースを取得できます。
to count the odds
オッズを数える
I can work out the odds
私は確率を計算することができます
These probabilities are called language models
これらの確率は言語モデルと呼ばれます
what about after this
この後はどうですか
This time I have a better way to string the sounds together
今回は音をつなぎ合わせるより良い方法があります
I have a better way of knowing what it is
それが何なのかを知るもっと良い方法があります
what's the matter
どうしたの
So what about the language model just now?
では、今の言語モデルはどうなるのでしょうか？
I use the example below
以下の例を使用します
Maybe it's easier for Chinese people to imagine
中国人にとっては想像しやすいかもしれない
here is a sentence
ここに文があります
This sentence is called
この文はと呼ばれます
Two people in Taitung are missing
台東市で2人が行方不明
This is a sentence from the TV news
これはテレビニュースの一文です
but what?
でも何？
Because many sounds are similar
似た音が多いので
I can spell a lot of weird words in no time
すぐにたくさんの奇妙な単語を綴ることができます
strange word come
変な言葉が来る
For example, say Haoyu
たとえば、ハオユと言います。
It seems to be temple language
寺語だそうです
Also like pottery
陶器も好き
so constantly
とても絶えず
also looks like gratuitous
無償にも見える
What about Taitung?
台東はどうですか？
much like too much wait
待ちすぎたようなもの
So many possible words can be spelled out
非常に多くの可能な単語を綴ることができます
We draw it into a graph called a word graph
それをワードグラフと呼ばれるグラフに描画します
The horizontal axis in this graph is time.
このグラフの横軸は時間です。
any line is some possible word
どの行も候補となる単語です
between two points
2点の間
Our vertical axis has no special meaning
縦軸に特別な意味はない
just connect all the words in there
そこにあるすべての単語を接続するだけです
Each path here is a possible answer
ここでの各パスは可能な答えです
We need to know that there is only this
これしかないということを私たちは知らなければなりません
is the correct answer
が正しい答えです
nothing else is right
他に何も正しくありません
That's the role of the language model
それが言語モデルの役割です
We want him to figure it out and tell me
私たちは彼にそれを理解して私に教えてもらいたいのです
The two missing in Taitung
台東で2人行方不明
The odds are much higher than this
確率はこれよりはるかに高い
What escape is too heavy for no reason, etc.
理由もなく逃げるのは重すぎる、など。
Then this is the function we just talked about
これが先ほど話した関数です
Then this needs to be trained with a text database.
次に、これをテキスト データベースでトレーニングする必要があります。
Then this needs to use the sound database for training, etc.
次に、これをサウンドデータベースなどでトレーニングする必要があります。
Well, after understanding this
さて、これを理解した上で
then we need to know the next thing
それから次のことを知る必要があります
then you can notice all my arrows now
そうすれば、今、私のすべての矢に気づくことができます
We all know this is coming
私たちは皆、これが来ることを知っています
what is this doing
これは何をしているのですか
He has a lot to do
彼にはやるべきことがたくさんある
He took all the items in
彼はすべての品物を持ち込んだ
He also put this acoustic model
彼はまた、この音響モデルを置きました
take the words in
言葉を取り入れて
All languages ​​are included
すべての言語が含まれています
Other profitable export complaints
他得輸出文句
This man is very powerful
この人はとても力強い人だ
This person is called a language model
この人は言語モデルと呼ばれます
language decoding
言語デコード
what is he doing
彼は何をしているの
We use the following figure to explain
次の図を使用して説明します
first thing is
まず第一のことは
We're going to point the word now
今からその言葉を指摘してみます
build a number
数字を構築する
word points
単語のポイント
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
for example
例えば
s followed by a is called s
sの後にaが続くものはsと呼ばれます
it's a word
それは言葉です
s followed by e
sの後にeが続く
This is speak
これは話すことです
it's a word
それは言葉です
Here connect ch to speak
次にchを接続して話します
it's a word blah blah
それは何とかという言葉です
I assume that there are 60,000 common English words
一般的な英単語は 60,000 個あると思います
My side is 60,000 words connected here
私の側はここでつながっている60,000の言葉です
become a tree
木になる
any line on a tree
木の上のどの線でも
or a jug
または水差し
is a Hidden Markov Model
は隠れマルコフモデルです
Because it's all a model
全部モデルだから
When you go to the end of every road is a word
すべての道の終わりに行くとき、それは言葉です
or a word
または一言
what we call a leaf
私たちが葉と呼ぶもの
a leaf on a tree
木の葉
So what?
だから何？
I give us any voice
私たちにどんな声でもかけます
I'll start here
ここから始めます
Go all the way down to calculate the score for each path
最後まで進み、各パスのスコアを計算します
So where does this score go
さて、このスコアはどこへ行くのか
I knew the signal here
ここの信号は知っていた
is say what is the score
スコアは何ですかと言う
What is the score of the speech when you come here, etc.
ここに来たときのスピーチの点数は何点ですか、など
Then why should I be a tree?
では、なぜ私は木でなければならないのでしょうか？
That's because only in this way
それはこの方法だけだからです
I can use the same unit without double counting
二重カウントせずに同じ単位を使用できます
For example, this speak and speech
たとえば、このスピーチとスピーチ
The road ahead is a good score
これからの道は良いスコアです
only the end here is different
ここの終わりだけが違う
get two points etc.
2点獲得など
After this we have to understand
この後、私たちは理解する必要があります
I don't know the score of a word until I finish walking
歩き終わるまで単語の点数は分からない
That's because I'm a continuous voice
それは私が声を出し続けるからです
So a word is followed by all possible words
したがって、単語の後には考えられるすべての単語が続きます
so what will it be
それで、それは何になりますか
will be like this
このようになります
The end of each word is connected to the next tree
各単語の終わりは次の木につながっています
So let's say this has 60,000 common words
これに一般的な単語が 60,000 個含まれているとします。
Go to the end after every word
すべての単語の後に最後に移動する
Just start picking the next tree
次の木を選び始めてください
The tree has 60,000 leaves
その木には6万枚の葉がある
Go to the bottom and pick up the next tree, etc.
一番下に行って次の木などを拾います。
So this is a primeval forest expanded by word point trees
これは単語点木によって拡張された原生林です
There are thousands of numbers in it
そこには何千もの数字が含まれています
Then I'm going to find the answer in it
そうしたら、その中で答えを見つけるつもりです
Then this is what we have to do in the language code block just now.
次に、これが言語コード ブロックで今行わなければならないことです。
Okay, this probably explains how we recognize human voices.
さて、これは私たちが人間の声をどのように認識するかをおそらく説明しています。
Next, I will talk about Chinese speech technology
次に中国語の音声技術についてお話します。
Why is it the same as Western languages?
なぜ西洋の言語と同じなのでしょうか？
That's because our Chinese language structure is very special
それは私たちの中国語の構造が非常に特殊だからです
What about the first one?
最初のものはどうですか？
every word has its meaning
すべての言葉には意味がある
And what we really mean by a sentence are words, not characters.
そして、文が実際に意味するものは文字ではなく単語です。
What does the word mean, and what does the word mean?
その言葉は何を意味し、その言葉は何を意味するのでしょうか？
sometimes relevant and sometimes irrelevant
時には関連性があり、時には無関係です
For example, our small bookstore is a store that sells books.
たとえば、私たちの小さな書店は本を販売する店です。
This means directly related
これは直接関係があることを意味します
University is not a big study
大学は大した学問ではない
But he has something to do with university and school.
しかし、彼は大学や学校と何らかの関係があります。
What about the bachelor? It's not a glowing stick.
独身者はどうですか? それは光る棒ではありません。
But he probably has something to do with light and stick
でも彼はおそらく光と棒に何か関係があるでしょう
a little bit less
少し少ない
Does the wind follow the flow?
風は流れに従うのか？
it's harder to say
言うのは難しいです
so different words
とても違う言葉
It has a complex relationship with the meaning of the word
言葉の意味と複雑な関係がある
so i see a word
それで単語が分かりました
or hear a word
または言葉を聞いてください
What exactly does that mean
それは正確にどういう意味ですか
This is quite complicated
これはかなり複雑です
Furthermore, our Chinese words have no boundaries
さらに、私たちの中国語の言葉には境界がありません
in the sentence
文の中で
And even the definition of the word is not clear
そして言葉の定義すら明確ではない
For example, in this sentence
たとえば、この文では
everyone see
誰もが見る
computer is a word
コンピューターは言葉だ
technology is a word
テクノロジーは言葉だ
is a word
言葉です
computer technology is a word
コンピューターテクノロジーは言葉です
computer technology is also a word
コンピューターテクノロジーも言葉です
which word is a word
どの単語が単語ですか
actually
実際
definition is ambiguous
定義があいまいです
The words in everyone's mind are different
心の中の言葉は人それぞれ違う
Furthermore, many of our small words can be connected in series at will
さらに、私たちの小さな言葉の多くは、自由に直列に接続できます。
become a big word
大きな言葉になる
For example, the terrorist attack in New York
例えば、ニューヨークのテロ攻撃
Our long words can be arbitrarily shortened into short words
私たちの長い単語は任意に短い単語に短縮できます
For example, Taiwan University has become too big
例えば、台湾大学は大きくなりすぎました。
Then what
じゃあ何
some words can be split
いくつかの単語は分割できる
For example, Lee Teng-hui becomes former President Lee Teng-hui
たとえば、李登輝は李登輝元総統になります。
Then what
じゃあ何
You can take a bath and take a comfortable big bath
入浴も快適な大きなお風呂に入ることができます
Everyone should understand that a bath is not a thing
お風呂は特別なものではないことを理解する必要があります
So instead of washing an apple
だからリンゴを洗う代わりに
this is a bath
ここはお風呂です
But this bath can be taken apart
でもこのお風呂は分解できるんです
etc.
等
Therefore, each of our words is independent and interesting like this
だからこうやって言葉一つ一つが独立していて面白いんです
So new words are generated automatically every day
新しい単語が毎日自動的に生成される
For example, gasoline and electric palms
たとえば、ガソリンや電気のヤシ
this is the new word
これは新しい言葉です
We don't need to define what it is
それが何であるかを定義する必要はありません
Everyone knows
みんな知ってる
etc.
等
Top too wind
トップは風が強すぎる
word everyone knows this time
今回は誰もが知っている言葉
But will they be in the dictionary
でも辞書に載るだろうか
80% of them are not in the dictionary
80％は辞書に載っていない
Therefore our words are infinite
したがって私たちの言葉は無限です
We are unlikely to be inside a dictionary
私たちが辞書の中にいる可能性は低い
contains all the words
すべての単語が含まれています
Did you notice when I just said
私が今言ったときに気づきましたか
There must be a dictionary in this method
このメソッドには辞書が必要です
But Chinese dictionaries are difficult to make
でも中国語の辞書は作るのが難しい
the second
二番目
We also have a very special structure
私たちも非常に特殊な構造を持っています
That is, we are word for word
つまり、私たちは一言一句
every word has a sound
すべての言葉には音がある
But the number of sounds is very small
ただし音数はかなり少ないです
Everyone knows our Chinese
誰もが私たちの中国語を知っています
The total number of sounds is about 1300
総音数は約1300音
We have at least 80,000 commonly used characters
一般的に使用される文字は少なくとも 80,000 文字あります
More than 8000
8000個以上
Therefore, each sound can have many phonetic characters
したがって、それぞれの音には多くの表音文字が含まれる可能性があります。
have different meanings
異なる意味を持つ
so you hear a voice
だから声が聞こえる
don't know what word it is
何の言葉か分かりません
then another point
それからもう一つの点
we are tonal language
私たちは声調言語です
I just said it
さっき言いました
so different tones give me different words
とても異なるトーンが私に異なる言葉を与えます
different meaning
違う意味
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
you will understand immediately
あなたはすぐに理解するでしょう
For example, the two sounds of one and ten
たとえば、1と10の2つの音
They all have four tones and many homophonic characters.
それらはすべて 4 つの声調と多くの同音異義語の文字を持っています。
We can make up a lot of words with unison
ユニゾンでたくさんの言葉を作ることができる
For example
例えば
Here is a time, a time, a time, a time, a time
ここは時間、時間、時間、時間、時間です
In fact, there are many, many
実際には、たくさんあります
I just give these few examples
これらの例をいくつか挙げます
you will understand
あなたは理解するでしょう
if i don't know its tone
その音色が分からないなら
It's really hard for me to know what it's talking about
何のことを言っているのかを理解するのは本当に難しいです
Furthermore
さらに
we have different voices
私たちは異なる声を持っています
can form a myriad of words
無数の単語を形成できる
so our voice
だから私たちの声
Grasp the sound inside from the sound
音の中から音を掴む
his difficulty is
彼の困難は
quite high
かなり高い
We actually have many words with the same pronunciation
実は同じ発音の単語がたくさんあります
You may never have felt
あなたは一度も感じたことがないかもしれません
Because we don't have to worry about it when we talk
話すときは気にしなくていいから
For example
例えば
The intersection of Research Institute Road and Zhongxiao East Road
研究院路と忠孝東路の交差点
Then of course what I'm talking about is this intersecting
それからもちろん、私が話しているのは、これが交差しているということです
You don't have to expect that intersection
その交差点を予期する必要はない
etc.
等
This is what we humans can do
これが私たち人間にできることです
machine you have to let the machine know
マシンに知らせなければなりません
That is to say, our few limited tones
つまり、私たちの数少ない限定トーン
Carries extremely rich linguistic messages
非常に豊かな言語メッセージを伝える
Then the hierarchical language unit of sound is Western language
すると、音の階層的な言語単位は西洋語になります。
pinyin but not in the language
ピンインはあるが言語ではない
Again, the order of our words in the play
もう一度、劇中の言葉の順序を
is quite free
かなり自由です
give an example
例を挙げる
these few words
このいくつかの言葉
I'm leaving at 6:30 tomorrow morning
明日の朝6時半に出発します
These words form a sentence
これらの単語は文を形成します
I mean everyone will understand right away
つまり誰もがすぐに理解できるでしょう
but you know
しかし、あなたは知っています
How many ways are there?
方法は何通りありますか?
at least these
少なくともこれらの
I can be 6:30 tomorrow morning
明日の朝6時半には行けるよ
i want to go
私は行ってみたい
Or I will leave at 6:30 tomorrow morning
それとも明日の朝6時半に出発します
or wait and wait
それとも待って待って
So why?
なぜ？
Use Mandarin voice to search Chinese information
北京語音声を使用して中国語情報を検索する
what kind of problems
どのような問題があるのか
then you can immediately think of
そうすればすぐに思いつくことができます
The first is because the information network is alive
1つ目は情報ネットワークが生きているからです
Chinese thoughts keep appearing every day
中国思想は日々現れ続ける
And the mind is not in the dictionary
そして心は辞書に載っていない
is difficult
難しい
But what we are looking for is often heart words
でも私たちが探しているのは心の言葉であることが多い
those are our keywords
それが私たちのキーワードです
For example
例えば
I want to order the top Taifeng Xiehuang Xiaolongbao
一番上の太峰謝黄小籠包を注文したいです
It is quite possible that the Internet is going to say that
インターネットがこう言う可能性は十分にあります
But this thing is not in the dictionary
でもこれは辞書に載ってない
This thing is not in the dictionary
こんなことは辞書に載っていない
Can you catch it just based on these sounds?
この音だけで聞き取れますか？
Wait these are examples of this
待ってください、これらはその例です
Typhoon Nali
台風ナリ
Definitely not in the dictionary
確かに辞書には載ってない
But the keyword you want is this
でも欲しいキーワードはこれ
these are keywords
これらはキーワードです
Words in user commands and target information
ユーザーコマンド内の単語とターゲット情報
often inconsistent
しばしば矛盾する
for example
例えば
So say I'm looking for
それで、探していると言ってください
North Second High Road Conditions
北第二街道の道路状況
It is said on the Internet that there are too many vehicles on the Second Northern Expressway
第二北道は車が多すぎるとネットで言われています
The machine needs to know this is this
機械はこれがこれであることを認識する必要があります
otherwise you won't find
そうしないと見つからない
Different meanings
現在のハイフネーションを間違っていると、異なる意味が生じることがよくあります
For example, someone wants to go online to find a brain doctor.
たとえば、オンラインで脳の医師を見つけたいと考えている人がいるとします。
He found a lot of brain
彼はたくさんの脳を見つけた
But it doesn't look like a brain
でも脳には見えない
why
なぜ
Because there is a word break boundary in the middle
途中で単語区切りがあるため
it is computer science
それはコンピューターサイエンスです
Some people want to go online to find folk land
オンラインでフォークランドを見つけたい人もいる
The folk belief is called the God of the Land
民間信仰は土地の神と呼ばれる
Then he went to find a lot of land owners
それから彼はたくさんの土地所有者を探しに行きました
But it's strange why the Landlord has a policy
しかしなぜ大家が方針を持っているのか不思議です
you find out it wasn't
そうではなかったことがわかります
Because he's talking about public ownership of land and so on.
土地の公有化などの話をしているからです。
Of course, there are errors in speech recognition and so on.
もちろん、音声認識などの誤差はあります。
These are all the problems you can imagine
これらはすべてあなたが想像できる問題です
Well, the above paragraph explains about this sound recognition
さて、上の段落ではこの音声認識について説明しています
how to do it
どうやってするの
So we're going to go into this sound search
それでは、この音の検索に進みます
Explain what we mean by sound search
サウンド検索の意味を説明する
What is Voice Information Search
音声情報検索とは
What is its relationship to text information search
文字情報検索との関係は？
This is the Google we know today
これが今日私たちが知っている Google です
I enter a text command
テキストコマンドを入力します
So what?
だから何？
The machine gave me a lot of files
マシンは私にたくさんのファイルをくれました
The text file contains all the things I want
テキスト ファイルには必要なものがすべて含まれています
but we know
でも私たちは知っています
All the instructions and documents
すべての説明書と書類
can it be voice
声でいいですか
so i can
だから私はできます
Use text commands to find audio files
テキスト コマンドを使用してオーディオ ファイルを検索する
The so-called audio file is a piece of audio
いわゆるオーディオファイルは音声の一部です
or a multimedia file
またはマルチメディア ファイル
a piece of multimedia
マルチメディアの一部
it contains speech but no text
音声は含まれていますが、テキストは含まれていません
I have to rely on the voice signal inside
内部の音声信号に頼らなければなりません
to judge the rocky beach
岩だらけのビーチを判断する
Then of course I can use voice commands to find text files
もちろん、音声コマンドを使用してテキスト ファイルを検索することもできます。
I can also use voice commands to find audio files
音声コマンドを使用してオーディオファイルを検索することもできます
These three are different things
この３つは別物です
three different questions
3つの異なる質問
Technically there are different proper nouns to describe it
技術的には、それを説明する別の固有名詞があります
But we call it what we call audio search
しかし、私たちはそれを音声検索と呼んでいます
Among these three things, today is the easiest and most mature
この3つの中で今日が一番簡単で大人っぽいです
It is the so-called voice search in the middle
いわゆる途中の音声検索です
In other words, use voice commands to find text files
つまり、音声コマンドを使用してテキスト ファイルを検索します。
Why does it actually just take the original text instruction
なぜ実際には元のテキストの指示だけが必要になるのですか
Find a text file and add one in front of it
テキスト ファイルを見つけてその前に追加します
When the voice command comes in, I will convert it into text first
音声コマンドが来たら、まずテキストに変換します
Just do the same later
後で同じことをするだけです
So like Google has its voice search
Google に音声検索があるのと同じように
that's what it is
それはそれです
Add a voice interface in front of Google's existing entire Google, etc.
Googleの既存のGoogle全体の前に音声インターフェースを追加するなど。
But in fact you can learn about us today
しかし実際には、今日私たちについて知ることができます
The main part of my talk today is the other two
今日の私の話の主な部分は残りの 2 つです
That is, if what I'm looking for is an audio file,
つまり、探しているものが音声ファイルの場合、
Whether it's through voice commands
音声コマンドによるかどうか
or text commands
またはテキストコマンド
No matter which one of them is basically
基本的にはどちらであっても
you imagine me to do things
あなたは私が何かをすることを想像します
turn voice into text
音声をテキストに変換する
Then I do a text search
次にテキスト検索を実行します
to find
見つけるには
if you said it before
前に言ったなら
it seems easy
簡単そう
The biggest problem is
最大の問題は
identification must be wrong
識別が間違っているに違いない
Our Speech Recognition Technology Today
現在の音声認識テクノロジー
still have a ton of errors
まだ大量のエラーがある
why wrong
なぜ間違っているのか
just now you can probably imagine
今ならきっと想像できるでしょう
We say that light cannot pour
光は降り注ぐことができないと言います
The two are different
両者は違います
so you need to know
だからあなたは知る必要があります
which signal is which word
どの信号がどの単語なのか
It's not easy
簡単ではない
first thought was
最初に考えたのは
I can use word graph to reduce
ワードグラフを使用して削減できます
The impact of misidentification
誤認の影響
as if we just saw
まるで見たばかりのように
in one sentence
一文で
I don't want to just recognize it as a sentence
単なる文章として認識したくない
Because there may be a lot of typos in it.
誤字脱字が多いかもしれないので。
But I can put all possible
でも、できる限りのことはできる
List all the words and turn them into a picture
すべての単語をリストして絵に変換します
In this case
この場合
all my words i can take into account
私が考慮できるすべての私の言葉
So the correct word is taken into account the chance
したがって、正しい単語は可能性を考慮に入れられます
greatly increased
大幅に増加した
But
しかし
This also adds a lot of wrong words
これにより、多くの間違った単語が追加されます
So I'm likely finding a bunch of wrong things
だから私はおそらく間違ったことをたくさん見つけるでしょう
while the correct word may still not be in it
正しい単語がまだ含まれていない可能性がありますが、
especially the words outside the dot
特にドットの外側の単語
it won't recognize it at all
まったく認識されなくなります
Of course I need a lot of calculations
もちろん、たくさんの計算が必要です
etc.
等
There are many other ways
他にもたくさんの方法があります
But I won't talk about this today
でも今日はこれについては話しません
let's talk about another thing
別のことについて話しましょう
What should I do if many words are not in the word points?
単語ポイントに含まれていない単語が多い場合はどうすればよいですか?
In fact, this is easier to deal with
実は、このほうが対処しやすいのです
Our usual approach today is to use so-called word units
今日の私たちの通常のアプローチは、いわゆる単語単位を使用することです
is a unit smaller than words
単語より小さい単位です
You immediately think that every language has its basic sounds
どの言語にも基本的な音があるとすぐに思います
Treat the basic sound as a unit
基本的なサウンドをユニットとして扱う
also can
こともできます
For example
例えば
suppose it's a word
それが言葉だと仮定して
W
の
It is made up of these four small basic sounds
これら 4 つの小さな基本音で構成されています
lexical units
語彙単位
But since it's not in the dot
でも点ではないので
So it will not appear in the word map
したがって、ワードマップには表示されません
This is a line of words in the word map
これは単語マップ内の単語の行です
they just don't have the word
彼らは言葉を持っていないだけです
Then these other ABCDs are also other word units
したがって、これらの他の ABCD も他の単語単位です
no
いいえ
But if you look closely, you'll see
でも、よく見てみるとわかります
I want this word is obviously hidden in this sub-word
この単語がこのサブ単語に明らかに隠されていることを望みます
So I just do the comparison at the subword level
したがって、サブワードレベルで比較を行うだけです
it can be compared
それは比較することができます
It doesn't matter if you don't recognize it
認識しなくても問題ない
So when I'm looking for Obama
それでオバマを探しているとき
Obama is in
オバマ氏は入っている
Although Obama is not in my dictionary
オバマは私の辞書には載っていないけれど
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
etc.
等
the subunit
サブユニット
In fact different languages
実際には異なる言語
The most suitable units are not the same
最適なユニットは同じではない
There are also people who directly use data to push him to do data driven
データドリブンを推進するためにデータを直接利用する人もいます。
That is to say, let the data tell me
つまり、データに教えてもらいましょう
Which is the best unit etc.
最強ユニットはどれかなどなど
good
良い
Let's talk about
について話しましょう
Some recent examples of using voice for information search
情報検索に音声を使用した最近の例
Compare some examples of relevant research
比較的関連性の高い研究の例
Most of this is what we did at National Taiwan University
これは主に国立台湾大学で行ったことです
So some simple examples
いくつかの簡単な例
Let everyone know
みんなに知らせて
Then the biggest problem we mentioned just now is that the identification will be wrong.
そうしますと、今申し上げた最大の問題は、識別が誤ってしまうということです。
Then we can imagine
それから私たちは想像することができます
This audio information search that most people want
多くの人が望んでいる音声情報検索
this is the picture
これが写真です
There's a whole bunch of audio digital content over here.
ここには大量のオーディオデジタルコンテンツがあります。
Do sound recognition first
最初に音声認識を行う
Turn every sentence into a word graph
すべての文を単語グラフに変換する
When the user enters a command
ユーザーがコマンドを入力するとき
For example, he wants to find Obama
たとえば、彼はオバマを見つけたいと思っています。
So we searched for the introduction
そこで紹介文を探しました
Just find it in these largest word graphs
これらの最大の単語グラフから見つけてください。
where is obama
オバマはどこですか
This idea is basically reasonable
この考えは基本的に合理的です
just saying he has the biggest problem
彼には最大の問題があると言っているだけです
Because he combines identification with search
彼は識別と検索を組み合わせているため、
into two units
2つのユニットに分けて
Train them individually and connect them together
個別にトレーニングし、それらを接続します
so misidentification leads to wrong search results
そのため、誤認により間違った検索結果が表示されます
how good your search is
あなたの検索の上手さ
may not be able to recover from misidentification
誤認から回復できない可能性がある
So what we think about is
そこで私たちが考えるのは、
How to break the frame of these two units connected in series
直列接続した2台のフレームを壊す方法
These two connect him forever
この二つは彼を永遠に結びつける
Can't fix this error
このエラーは修正できません
So after we break it down
それで、それを分解した後、
rethink a thing
物事を考え直す
Integrative thinking to reduce the impact of misidentification
誤認の影響を軽減するための統合的思考
Let's give a few examples of this
この例をいくつか挙げてみましょう
The first example is the so-called virtual correct feedback
最初の例は、いわゆる仮想正しいフィードバックです。
The idea is that if you're looking for Obama
アイデアは、オバマを探しているなら、ということです。
Suppose you already know that there is really Obama in a certain sentence
ある文の中に実際にはオバマが含まれていることをすでに知っていると仮定します。
Then other possible sentences that are similar to him can get extra points
その後、彼に似た他の考えられる文が追加ポイントを獲得できるようになります
the idea is simple
アイデアはシンプルです
The problem is how do I know which sentence is correct?
問題は、どの文が正しいかをどうやって知るかということです。
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
This way I'm assuming I'm doing the first search first
このように、最初の検索を最初に行うことを想定しています
get a bunch of results
たくさんの結果を得る
I become a search result
検索結果になります
Assuming the ex-en name inside is correct
中の元の名前が正しいと仮定します
so what will it be
それで、それは何になりますか
like this
このような
this is my command
これは私の命令です
like Obama
オバマのように
My machine got a bunch of results the first time I searched
私のマシンは、初めて検索したときに大量の結果を取得しました
is the search result
検索結果です
The machine at least judges that they all look like Obama
機械は少なくとも彼ら全員がオバマに似ていると判断する
I don't show this result to the user
この結果はユーザーには表示されません
Because there are many mistakes in it
間違いが多いので
I'll take the ex-en name in this first
最初に元の名前を使用します
assuming he's right
彼が正しいと仮定すると
So everyone else went to compare with him to see the similarity
そこで他のみんなは彼と比較して類似点を確認しました
Then if any of your voices follow the former name
もしあなたの声が以前の名前に続くなら
people are like
人民都像
That means he probably really has Obama.
それは、彼が本当にオバマを持っている可能性があることを意味します。
you can give him extra points
彼に追加点を与えることができます
Then I can reorder
それから再注文できます
After getting a better result
より良い結果が出た後は
users can see
ユーザーは見ることができます
do so
そうする
Mine is making considerable progress right now
私の場合は現在かなり進んでいます
because this is indeed
これは確かにそうだから
if they are all alike
それらがすべて同じであれば
I'm afraid he really has Obama.
彼は本当にオバマを持っているのではないかと思う
Then there is one thing to say
さて、ここで一つ言いたいことがある
How is this similarity calculated?
この類似性はどのように計算されるのでしょうか?
The similarity of this sound is difficult to calculate
この音の類似性を計算するのは困難です
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
Suppose this is statement XI
これがステートメント XI であると仮定します。
We feel like he has an Obama in him
彼の中にオバマがいるような気がする
But I opened the word map to see
でも、単語マップを開いて確認してみました
Not just one Obama, but several
オバマ大統領一人だけではなく、複数のオバマ大統領も
I'll just pick the one with the highest score.
スコアが最も高いものを選択します。
Let's say this is Obama
これがオバマだとしましょう
So where is the relative feature item ranked?
では、相対的な特徴項目は何位にランクされるのでしょうか?
This bunch of feature items
この目玉アイテムの数々
I'm assuming he's Obama
彼はオバマ氏だと思う
So what?
だから何？
another word from me
私からもう一言
kinda like having obama
オバマがいるようなもの
I'll just put that against Obama's bunch
それをオバマ陣営と対立させてやるよ
Take out that part too
その部分も取り出して
so i want to make them
だから作りたいです
The two Obamas compare
二人のオバマ大統領を比較する
do they look like
彼らは似ていますか
this is the problem
これが問題です
Because they are different in length
長さが違うので
different lengths
異なる長さ
Obama inside is different
オバマの内面は違う
how do i compare
どうやって比較すればいいですか
we need to make a
を作る必要があります
so-called dynamic time calibration
いわゆる動的時間校正
What does it mean
どういう意味ですか
if we look at
見てみたら
This picture probably understands
この写真なら分かるかも知れません
These are the two Obamas
この二人はオバマ大統領です
different length
異なる長さ
The sound of the wave in this bar is also different.
このバーでは波の音も違います。
how do i compare
どうやって比較すればいいですか
I put an Obama on the horizontal axis
横軸にオバマを置きました
In addition, Obama is on the heavy axis
さらにオバマは重軸に乗っている
If I draw the value of a certain parameter inside
内部の特定のパラメータの値を描画すると
they have changes like this
彼らはこのような変更を行っています
then you can imagine
それから想像してみてください
It is said that this point should be compared with this point
この点とこの点を比較する必要があると言われています
compare this with this
これとこれを比較してください
This is more like
これはもっと似ています
it means
その意味は
I want to be on this two-dimensional plane
この二次元にいたい
find a curve
曲線を見つける
That curve tells me who's up against whom
その曲線は誰が誰と対戦しているかを教えてくれる
right
右
Because they are different in length
長さが違うので
Here is a schematic
これが概略図です
The more realistic picture is the first
よりリアルな写真が最初です
this one
これです
This is the horizontal axis, the vertical axis, the two Obamas
これは横軸、縦軸、二人のオバマです
we understand that this is actually
これが実際にあることを私たちは理解しています
This painting is actually a ten-spectrum
この絵は実際には10のスペクトルです
The vertical axis is the frequency
縦軸は周波数です
this is the frequency
これが周波数です
then you can see that i am
そうすれば私がそうだということがわかります
A quantity is compared with a quantity
量と量を比較する
like this bunch of people said
この大勢の人が言ったように
This item is at the same time as here
この商品はこちらと同時です
A lot of items to compare and so on
比較項目なども豊富
then i will do this
それなら私はこれをやります
After ten them well
10 回も経ったら、
Let's compare again
もう一度比べてみましょう
let me know my accuracy
私の正確さを教えてください
my similarity
私の類似点
Okay, this is a method just mentioned
さて、これは先ほど述べた方法です
Let's think of another way
別の方法を考えてみましょう
we just said i assume
私たちはそう思うと言いました
In the search results, Qian Enming is correct
検索結果では、Qian Enming が正しいです。
It doesn't make sense
意味がありません
Why is Qian Enming right?
なぜ銭恩明が正しいのか？
I think another way should be
別の方法があるべきだと思います
I put all the search results
検索結果をすべて載せておきます
Take the similarity between the two
両者の類似点を考えてみましょう
to be used as a reference
参考として使用する
how to do it
どうやってするの
Then we can put the search results inside
次に、検索結果を中に入れることができます
every sentence
すべての文
Treat it as a node and turn it into a graph
それをノードとして扱い、グラフ化します。
Between points and points is the similarity between dramas
点と点の間にはドラマの類似点がある
as the score of their connection
接続のスコアとして
So a higher score means they are more like
したがって、スコアが高いほど、より似ていることを意味します
So the higher the score, the more similar it is
スコアが高いほど類似していることを意味します
We can do it with this
これでできるよ
For example, suppose the drama X1 is very similar to the two sentences of X2X3
たとえば、ドラマ X1 が X2X3 の 2 つの文に非常に似ているとします。
Because they have a strong connection
強い絆で結ばれているから
that they look alike
彼らは似ているということ
If X2X3 are high scores
X2X3がハイスコアの場合
Then X1 should be extra points
そうすると X1 が追加点になるはずです
In the same way, if X1X2 are all low scores
同様に、X1X2 がすべて低スコアの場合
Then X1 should be deducted points
そうすると X1 が減点されるはずです
that means
つまり
After we let all fractions flow on the graph
すべての分数をグラフ上に流した後
let it converge
収束させてください
This means that all similar sentences
つまり、同様の文はすべて
Because their connection score is high
接続スコアが高いため
they can reinforce each other
彼らはお互いを強化することができます
This mutually reinforcing confirmation makes all changes
この相互に強化される確認がすべての変化をもたらします
Yes, errors are reduced a lot
はい、エラーは大幅に減少しました
Then after confirming the reinforcement
そして補強を確認したら
We then confirm the results based on reinforcement
その後、強化に基づいて結果を確認します
to remake the sequence
シーケンスを作り直す
this time i am all sentences
今回は私がすべての文です
together to reinforce each other
一緒にお互いを強化する
So I'm not predestined
だから私は運命ではない
if i do
私が行った場合
Have my scores improved?
私のスコアは向上しましたか?
Immediately noticeable improvement
すぐに目に見える改善
This is the second example
これは 2 番目の例です
give another example
別の例を挙げてください
It's in machine learning
それは機械学習にあります
so-called supporting imager
いわゆるサポートイメージャ
We have learned about machine learning in recent years
私たちは近年機械学習について学びました
very popular topic
非常に人気のある話題
because machine learning
なぜなら機械学習は
We can do a lot of things that we couldn't do in the past
昔はできなかったことがたくさんできるようになります
An example here is
ここでの例は次のとおりです
so-called supporting imager
いわゆるサポートイメージャ
support victim machine
被害者のマシンをサポートする
or SVM
またはSVM
The basic idea is this
基本的な考え方はこれです
I'm still the same
私は今も同じです
After the user enters a command Obama
ユーザーがコマンドを入力した後 オバマ
I get a bunch of voices that might be Obama's
オバマのものかもしれない声がたくさん聞こえます
But I don't show this to users
ただし、これをユーザーには見せません
Because this is obviously wrong
これは明らかに間違っているので
then what should we do
じゃあどうすればいいのか
I'll take this as my payout result
これを支払い結果として受け取ります
Presupposition
前提
is right , as a right offense
それは正しい、正しい犯罪として
In the end Eun Myung assumed he was wrong
結局ウンミョンは自分が間違っていたと思った
make a mistake
間違える
Then, I'll build a
それから、私は
so-called supporting camera
いわゆるサポートカメラ
right and wrong examples
本当の例と間違った例
to build one between them
それらの間に一つを築くために
how to divide
分け方
After that, I take mine
その後、私は自分のものを取ります
What about the results of all the departures?
すべての出発の結果はどうですか？
Throw it into this camera
このカメラに投げ込んでください
let him reorder
彼に再注文させてください
get good , better sort
良くなる、より良い分類
The result is the result
結果は結果だ
users see
ユーザーが見る
Then here we have to explain a little bit
それから、ここで少し説明しなければなりません
This SVM or support camera
この SVM またはバック カメラ マシン
what is
とは
What it means is
それが意味するのは、
In phasor space there are two groups
フェーザー空間には 2 つのグループがあります
known phasor
既知のフェーザー
assuming these are correct
これらが正しいと仮定すると
these are wrong
これらは間違っています
I want to find a plane and divide them
飛行機を見つけて分けたい
what about this plane
この飛行機はどうですか
you may be like this
あなたはこうかもしれません
it could be
かもしれない
you want to take
あなたは取りたいですか
seem
思われる
this is the best why
これが最高です なぜか
because if you look at it this way
なぜならこうして見ると
it has the largest interval
間隔が最も大きいです
in other words
言い換えると
if you look at this
これを見たら
it's a little too close
少し近すぎる
Not very good
あまりよくない
if you look at it this way
こうやって見ると
it's a little too close
少し近すぎる
It's not good to be too close
近づきすぎるのは良くないよ
That's when it's going to be like this
その時はこうなるよ
They are separated by the largest
それらは最大のもので区切られています
I'll just put the closest point here
ここに最も近い点を置きます
this way for best results
最良の結果を得るにはこの方法で
This is the so-called support think two doses
これはいわゆるサポート思考の2回分です
After you get this flat separation
このフラットな分離を得た後
The new position phasor is thrown in
新しい位置フェーザーがスローされます
just use this to separate
これを使って分離するだけです
see it and know it's right
ただ見てください、そしてそれが正しいことがわかります
still wrong
まだ間違っています
Then I can actually use it
そしたら実際に使えるよ
distance from this plane
この飛行機からの距離
can be reordered
並べ替えることができます
Sort in this vertical direction
この縦方向に並べ替えます
i will know
私が知るだろう
Who is the most correct and so on
誰が一番正しいかなど
of course
もちろん
many times
何度も
There will be some exception errors
いくつかの例外エラーが発生します
For example
例えば
These are correct Obama
これらは正しいオバマだ
but there is one more
でももう一つある
For example, he was talking about
たとえば、彼が話していたのは、
The student who gave birth to Europe, how about his parents
ヨーロッパを生んだ学生、両親はどうですか
So what about Ou's parents?
では、Ouの両親はどうなったのでしょうか？
hey come in too
ねえ、あなたも入ってください
Then it's a wrong exception
それならそれは間違った例外だ
There is also the correct exception running to the
に対して実行される適切な例外もあります。
If you have to divide it like this, it will be too difficult.
こうやって分けないといけないとなると大変ですね。
So we usually allow some exception errors
したがって、通常はいくつかの例外エラーを許可します
So why can I
では、なぜできるのでしょうか
such planes cut them
そのような飛行機は彼らを切り裂く
And these two are the exceptions to the error
そして、これら 2 つはエラーの例外です
etc.
等
Of course, there are still many times, no matter how you do it.
もちろん、どうやっても回数はたくさんあります。
I'm actually having a hard time separating the two groups.
実は、この 2 つのグループを区別するのに苦労しています。
How can it be difficult to tell them apart?
それらを区別するのはどうして難しいのでしょうか?
We figured out how to use some mathematical models
いくつかの数学モデルの使用方法を見つけました
Convert it to a different or higher space
別の空間またはより高い空間に変換します
hope in that space
その空間に希望を
they can be cut and so on
カットなどもできます
Then these are the basic spirits of the phasor class
これらは phasor クラスの基本的な精神です
After understanding that, let's go back and read what we just said.
それを理解した後、今言ったことを見てみましょう
We just said, let's say he's looking for Obama
先ほども言いましたが、彼がオバマを探しているとしましょう
Then the first time I found out, the results are these
そして初めて知りましたが、結果はこうなりました
Then I don't show it to the user
その後、ユーザーには表示しません
Because he has a lot of
彼はたくさんのものを持っているので、
I just assume that the top N names are the correct examples
上位 N 個の名前が正しい例であると仮定しています。
The last N names are wrong examples
最後の N 個の名前は間違った例です
I just use this to go
これを使って出かけるだけです
A bunch of wrong and right to build a support item measuring machine
サポートアイテム測定機を作るための間違ったことと正しいことの塊
Then he told me where the real cutting plane is
それから彼は本当の切断面がどこにあるのか教えてくれました
So I threw all the output results in
だから私はすべての出力結果を投げました
According to the vertical distance of this plane
この飛行機の垂直距離によると
to reorder
並べ替える
Only the output results are shown to the user
出力結果のみがユーザーに表示されます
what's the result
結果は何ですか
Immediately there will be great progress, etc.
すぐに大きな進歩などが起こるでしょう。
I think the above few examples show how we can do something like this
上記のいくつかの例は、どのようにしてこのようなことができるかを示していると思います
Of course some people want to say
もちろん言いたい人もいるよ
if it is like this
このような場合
so can i just
それでいいですか
Since your speech recognition errors are so many
音声認識エラーが多すぎるため、
I don't want to recognize
認識したくない
because I can let the user directly use the
ユーザーに直接使用させることができるため、
input voice command
音声コマンドを入力する
Since your command is voice
コマンドは音声なので
I just follow this audio file on the Internet
インターネット上でこの音声ファイルをフォローするだけです
Just go and compare with those
行ってそれらと比較してください
Can I beat the signal?
信号を越えることはできるでしょうか？
This is the greatest benefit that can be done
これができる最大のメリットです
It's just that I forgot to identify
ただ識別するのを忘れていただけです
There is no such thing as misidentification.
誤認などというものはありません。
but it is difficult
でもそれは難しい
you know what we just said
私たちが今言ったことを知っていますか
It's different if you don't reach those two
その2つに届かなければ別です
the same person said the same reason
同じ人が同じ理由を言った
can be very different
大きく異なる可能性があります
What's more, different people say the same sentence
さらに、異なる人が同じ文を言っている
is quite different
かなり違う
So it's very likely that you've been comparing for a long time
つまり、長い間比較してきた可能性が非常に高いです
not easy to match
合わせるのは簡単ではない
So so far
これまでのところ
This is an important research direction
これは重要な研究の方向性です
However, due to the lack of identification
ただし、身分証明書がないため、
The correct total value to compare against
比較する正しい合計値
So it's still pretty bad
だからまだかなり悪いです
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
The dynamic time calibration we just talked about
先ほど話した動的時間校正
It's a very good way to compare
比較するのに非常に良い方法です
This is the various sounds in the sound file
これはサウンドファイル内のさまざまな音です
This is a phonetic designation such as
などの発音記号です。
He's looking for Obama
彼はオバマを望んでいる
I'll take him
彼を連れて行きます
so compare i need
だから比較する必要がある
Two by two I go to find between them
二人ずつ二人の間を探しに行く
the curve that can be compared
比較できる曲線
Then go compare and so on
それから比較してみましょう
This calculation is very large
この計算は非常に膨大です
In order to reduce this calculation
この計算を減らすために
can also be done like this
このようにすることもできます
That is, I first put the voice in
つまり、最初に声を入れたのです
The more similar parts are cut into sections
より類似した部分がセクションに切り分けられます
that's almost one tone
ほぼワントーンですね
For example this could be O
たとえば、これは O です。
this is 8
これは8です
This wave R
この波 R
This is Ma Mo R and so on
こちらはマ・モ・Rなど
if so
もしそうなら
I will compare it piece by piece
一つ一つ比較していきます
can do like this
このようにできます
But what?
でも何？
This is much less computationally intensive
これは計算量がはるかに少ないです
but
しかし
I can't be more correct
これ以上正確なことはありません
Of course there is a better way
もちろんもっと良い方法があります
we feel today
私たちは今日感じます
At this stage it looks like the best way to do this is to
現段階では、これを行うための最良の方法は次のとおりです
use the model
モデルを使用する
That is to say, in this audio file
つまり、この音声ファイルでは、
all voices
すべての声
I have built it into
に組み込んでいます
The hidden Markov model we just talked about
先ほど話した隠れマルコフモデル
The biggest advantage of becoming a model is that
モデルになる最大のメリットは
it has a lot of chance
それはチャンスがたくさんある
So put every possible variation
可能な限りのバリエーションをすべて入れてください
It's all in there
すべてはそこにある
So why?
なぜ？
To deal with different people saying the same sentence
異なる人が同じ文を言っている場合に対処する
What about the difference in the signal?
さまざまな信号についてはどうですか?
This model works better
このモデルのほうがうまく機能します
Therefore
したがって
What if the user says I want to find Obama?
ユーザーがオバマを見つけたいと言ったらどうしますか?
This, this, using this voice signal
これ、これ、この音声信号を使って
What about these models?
これらのモデルはどうでしょうか？
is more effective
より効果的です
This is how this series of ideas
この一連のアイデアはこんな感じです
Another idea called concept comparison
概念比較と呼ばれる別のアイデア
What is concept comparison?
コンセプト比較とは何ですか？
It means that if the user says that I want Obama
つまり、ユーザーが「オバマが欲しい」と言った場合、
Of course the machine I hope he gives me all the sentences with Obama in them
もちろん、機械はオバマが含まれるすべての文章を私に返してくれることを願っています
But there are some sentences in
しかし、中にはいくつかの文があります
Without the word Obama
オバマという言葉がなければ
He was talking about something from the White House.
彼はホワイトハウスからの何かについて話していました。
I wish I could find it too
私も見つけられたらいいのですが
Because he's what I want
なぜなら彼は私が望むものだから
this means it works
これは機能することを意味します
Just without the literal Obama
文字通りのオバマがいないだけで
In other words, we have the so-called literal comparison and conceptual comparison.
言い換えれば、いわゆる文字通りの比較と概念的な比較があります。
Literal comparison is easier
文字通りの比較が簡単です
Just ask Obama
オバマさんに聞いてみてください
Concept comparison seems to be much more difficult
コンセプトの比較はかなり難しいようです
Because you need to know the White House and Obama
ホワイトハウスとオバマについて知る必要があるからです
Actually, they are two very common words.
実際、これらは非常に一般的な 2 つの単語です。
That is to say, I want to find sentences related to meaning
つまり、意味に関係する文章を探したいのです。
Even if it doesn't include your directive
たとえあなたの指示が含まれていないとしても
There are many ways to do this
これを行うには多くの方法があります
Below I think two simple examples to illustrate
以下に 2 つの簡単な例を示します。
what do they mean
どういう意味ですか
first method
最初の方法
I'm trying to analyze the sentence inside
中の文を分析しようとしています
hidden semantics
隠されたセマンティクス
this is what we call
これを私たちはそう呼んでいます
Latent Semantic Analysis
潜在意味解析
There are many ways of doing this
これを行うには多くの方法があります
is a simple example
簡単な例です
so-called probabilistic analysis
いわゆる確率分析
The so-called PLSA
いわゆるPLSA
how to explain this
これをどう説明するか
We use a very simple concept to think
私たちは非常にシンプルな概念を使って考えます
Let's say it's a bunch of files
それが大量のファイルだとしましょう
Or a bunch of voice files would work too
または、大量の音声ファイルも機能します
Text files can also
テキスト ファイルでも、
if in terms of voice
声に関して言えば
a bunch of sentences
たくさんの文
there are many words in them
それらにはたくさんの言葉があります
There are many words in each
それぞれにたくさんの言葉が入っています
The computer really doesn't know which word
コンピュータは本当にどの単語を知らないのか
what word does it have to do with
それはどんな言葉と関係がありますか
or something
か何か
still don't know
まだわかりません
But a computer can do one thing
しかし、コンピュータができることは 1 つあります
it can be found saying
と言っているのが見つかります
inside this pile of files
このファイルの山の中に
always have these words
常にこの言葉を持ってください
there are these words again
またこの言葉が出てきました
So we can imagine
それで私たちは想像することができます
These documents and these words
この書類とこの言葉
maybe talking about a
たぶん、について話している
the concept or theme
コンセプトやテーマ
These dictionaries are similar to this
これらの辞書はこれに似ています
It should be another concept
それは別の概念であるはずです
or another topic
または別の話題
For example
例えば
if this was obama
これがオバマだったら
This is the economic policy of the United States
これがアメリカの経済政策です
this is the presidential election
これは大統領選挙です
this is probably a theme
おそらくこれがテーマです
if this is bin laden
これがビンラディンなら
this is iran
ここはイランです
this is baghdad
ここはバグダッドです
it might be another thing
それは別のことかもしれない
etc.
等
If you think about it this way
こうやって考えてみると
what we do here
私たちがここで何をしているのか
In fact, it is assumed that there is a series of
実際には、次のような系列があると想定されます。
hidden theme or concept
隠れたテーマやコンセプト
that's it
それでおしまい
Then we base the vocabulary on
次に、語彙をベースにします
in a different file
別のファイルに
Co-Occurrence Statistics
共起統計
to analyze what themes are
テーマが何かを分析する
so i will know
だから私は知っています
Obama and the White House
オバマとホワイトハウス
belong to the same subject
同じ主題に属している
so they are
だから彼らは
I though this directive is Obama
この指令はオバマ大統領だと思う
I can also find those
それらも見つけることができます
stuff in the white house
ホワイトハウスにあるもの
it's a concept
それはコンセプトです
that another way
それは別の方法です
This so-called instruction extension
このいわゆる命令拡張
query expansion
クエリ拡張
Let's use a simple example
簡単な例を使ってみましょう
keeps stating that he assumes the user enters Obama
ユーザーがオバマ政権に入るのを想定していると言い続けている
I made this instruction into a so-called instruction model
この命令をいわゆる命令モデルにしました
It's nothing special. He's just an Obama.
それは特別なことではありません、彼はただのオバマです
That's all the words only W2 the word Obama
W2 オバマという言葉だけがこれだけです
Yes probability is 1, everything else is 0
はい、確率は 1、その他はすべて 0
Then I'll do the first search with this command
次に、このコマンドで最初の検索を実行します
get my search results
検索結果を取得する
I can't allow users to see the search results
ユーザーに検索結果の表示を許可できません
because there are many mistakes
間違いが多いので
Then I'll assume ex Eun Myung is right
だったら元ウンミョンが正しいと思うよ
Count what words are used in them
その中でどのような単語が使われているかを数える
For example, there are Obamas here, there are Obamas here
たとえば、ここにもオバマがいる、ここにもオバマがいる
But here's the White House, he also has the White House
でもここがホワイトハウス、彼にもホワイトハウスがある
That means the White House should be what you want too.
つまり、ホワイトハウスもあなたが望むものでなければならないということです。
So I use this to make a new instruction model
したがって、これを使用して新しい命令モデルを作成します
just add the white house
ホワイトハウスを追加するだけです
But in turn, there's bin Laden over here.
しかし今度は、ここにビンラディンがいます。
no bin laden here
ここにはビンラディンはいない
bin laden better not
ビンラディンはやめたほうがいい
Wait so I can create a new command
新しいコマンドを作成するのでお待ちください
It is a lot more than the original instruction
元の指示よりもはるかに多くの内容です
just expanded
拡張したばかりの
I'll find it again with this command
このコマンドでもう一度見つけます
I only show users what I find out
私が見つけたものだけをユーザーに表示します
This is the so-called instruction extension
これはいわゆる命令拡張です
Another big problem is
もう一つの大きな問題は、
Even if we use Google to find text files today
たとえ今日Googleを使ってテキストファイルを見つけたとしても
We also know that it is helpful for users to interact with the system
また、ユーザーがシステムを操作することが有益であることもわかっています。
So for example, if you enter who
たとえば、「who」と入力すると、
After he showed me a bunch of stuff
いろいろなものを見せてもらったあと、
let me click what to wait
何を待つかをクリックさせてください
This interaction is very important
このやりとりはとても大切です
But with English or multimedia content
ただし、英語またはマルチメディア コンテンツの場合
The biggest problem is that it's not easy to render on the screen
最大の問題は、画面上にレンダリングするのが簡単ではないことです
So it's not as clear as text
したがって、テキストほど明確ではありません
is not easy to choose
選ぶのは簡単ではありません
I can't listen to every one of them
全部を聞くことはできない
After listening to it, I found that it wasn't what I wanted.
聞いてみると、それは私が望んでいたものではないことがわかりました。
In this way, the user writes that the machine must be thrown away
このようにして、ユーザーはマシンを廃棄する必要があると書きます。
So how do we make it easy for users to
では、ユーザーが簡単にできるようにするにはどうすればよいでしょうか
Browse click
参照してクリック
like text
テキストのような
this is a big problem
これは大きな問題です
I found a lot of things and don't know what to do
たくさんのことを見つけたけど何をすればいいのかわからない
how to do this
これを行う方法
We are thinking of the following methods
以下の方法を考えております
what about the first one
最初のものはどうですか
I think of a way to replace the digital content of these voices only
この音声だけをデジタルコンテンツに置き換える方法を考えます
Build some language sessions of its keywords, etc.
キーワードなどの言語セッションを構築します。
Then create its title, create its summary
次に、タイトルを作成し、概要を作成します
Then what
じゃあ何
I try to build some knowledge structure
いくつかの知識構造を構築しようとしています
let me help me click to browse
クリックして閲覧するのを手伝ってください
has a nice user interface
素晴らしいユーザーインターフェースを持っています
Then what
じゃあ何
I allow users to talk to my system
ユーザーが私のシステムと会話できるようにします
I'm going to say these things quickly
こういったことをすぐに言うつもりです
For example
例えば
First
初め
We say that in this audio file
この音声ファイルではそう言っています
We hope to catch some key
何か鍵を掴めることを願っています
Key words or key phrases
キーワードまたはキーフレーズ
There are only two
2つしかない
a word is called a keyword
単語はキーワードと呼ばれます
Otherwise, multiple words are called key phrases
それ以外の場合、複数の単語はキー フレーズと呼ばれます
Then we need to find these things out
次に、これらのことを見つける必要があります
The first question is that the key phrase has several words
最初の質問は、キーワードに複数の単語が含まれているかどうかです。
How do I know which words together form a key phrase?
どの単語が一緒になってキー フレーズを形成しているかを知るにはどうすればよいですか?
For example
例えば
President Barack Obama
バラク・オバマ大統領
This is an obvious key phrase
これは明らかなキーワードです
How do I know it should be a key phrase?
それがキーフレーズであるべきだとどうやって判断できますか?
for example
例えば
If I found in my data
私のデータで見つかった場合
the right side of america is often followed by the same word
アメリカの右側には同じ単語が続くことがよくあります
the word is called president
その言葉は大統領と呼ばれます
American presidents are often followed by the same word to the right
アメリカの大統領の後には右側に同じ言葉が続くことが多い
that word is called obama
その言葉はオバマと呼ばれます
But President Obama's right
しかしオバマ大統領は正しい
followed by many different words
その後に色々な言葉が続く
that means
つまり
This should be the right border of a phrase
これはフレーズの右側の境界線である必要があります
Similarly I can also find
同様に、私も見つけることができます
This is the left boundary of a phrase
これはフレーズの左側の境界です
because there are many
たくさんあるから
so I can use various statistics for each context
そのため、コンテキストごとにさまざまな統計を使用できます
to figure out its boundaries
その境界を見極めるために
Knowing the boundaries doesn't mean he must be the key phrase
境界を知っているからといって、彼がキーワードでなければならないというわけではない
So we still need a lot of other knowledge to confirm him
したがって、彼を確認するにはまだ多くの他の知識が必要です
For example
例えば
The first confirmation is a mistake
最初の確認は間違いです
Everyone knows
みんな知ってる
when the speaker says key words
話者がキーワードを言うとき
or key phrases
またはキーフレーズ
it often speaks a little slower
少しゆっくり話すことが多いです
the volume will be higher
音量は大きくなります
The change in pitch will be a little bigger
ピッチの変化が少し大きくなります
That's the obvious message to me
それが私への明白なメッセージです
it is the keyword
それがキーワードです
again the word itself
またまた言葉そのもの
we could have just said
私たちはただ言うこともできたでしょう
We can analyze its underlying themes
その根底にあるテーマを分析できます
or concept
またはコンセプト
I can based on its theme
テーマに基づいてできます
or concept to know
または知っておくべき概念
Is it a keyword
キーワードですか
For example
例えば
the word obama
オバマという言葉
possibly in two themes
おそらく2つのテーマで
high probability
高い確率で
This is the US presidential election
これはアメリカ大統領選挙です
This is America
ここはアメリカです
West Season Bin Laden
ウェスト・シーズン・ビンラディン
Both of these are highly likely
どちらも可能性が高いですね
Other chances are very low
それ以外の可能性は非常に低いです
Let's say this is the Oscars
これがオスカーだとしましょう
This is a baseball game in Taiwan
これは台湾の野球の試合です
None of them have Obama
オバマ氏は誰もいない
This looks like a keyword
これがキーワードのようです
why keywords
なぜキーワード
Usually only concentrated in
通常はのみに集中しています
A handful of conceptual themes inside
いくつかの概念的なテーマが含まれています
This is for example a
これは例えば、
today or morning
今日か朝
or very
または非常に
This kind of word appears in almost every topic
この種の単語はほとんどすべてのトピックで登場します
That means it's probably not a keyword, and so on.
つまり、それはおそらくキーワードではない、などということになります。
Of course there are other important knowledge
もちろん他にも重要な知識はあります
For example, the frequency of occurrence of the word
たとえば、単語の出現頻度
its part of speech etc.
その品詞など
it's all about
それはすべてです
What I just talked about is how to extract keywords
今話したのはキーワードの抽出方法です
Let's talk about how to do file extraction
ファイル抽出の方法について話しましょう
These will be shown to you in actual combat later.
これらは後ほど実戦で披露します。
Then the voice file we hope to be able to extract
次に、抽出できると期待される音声ファイル
Automatically draw a pill
自動的に錠剤を描画します
How to draw it? For example, this is a voice file
どうやって描くかというと、例えば音声ファイルです。
There are six sentences in it
その中には6つの文があります
A circle in each sentence means a word
各文の丸は単語を意味します
This blue one means correct identification
この青いのは正しい識別を意味します
Red indicates identification error
赤は識別エラーを示します
if i have a way to find out in there
そこを知る方法があるなら
two particularly important sentences
特に重要な 2 つの文
wrap it up
急いでください
as medicine
薬として
What if I treat it as after taking the medicine?
薬を飲んだ後と同じように扱ったらどうなりますか？
It can be played back with its original sound
原音のまま再生可能
As long as it is the original sound played out
再生される原音である限り
it's the wrong question
それは間違った質問です
it all sounds right
それはすべて正しいように聞こえます
What about this?
これはどうですか？
is what we call this sound
それを私たちはこの音と呼んでいます
voice summary
音声概要
So of course the question is how to choose the drama
さて、問題はドラマをどう選ぶかです。
There are several basic principles in the selection of plays
作品の選択にはいくつかの基本原則があります
for example
例えば
Anything that contains more
それ以上のものを含むもの
more important word
もっと大切な言葉
or words that look more like keywords
またはキーワードに似た単語
it's more important
それはもっと重要です
it contains
を含む
Because I can analyze concepts now
概念を分析できるようになったので
So if it contains the concept
つまり、コンセプトが含まれている場合は、
Closer to the concept of the full text
全文の概念に近づく
that should be more important
それはもっと重要であるべきです
In addition
加えて
What if a sentence has been selected?
文が選択されている場合はどうなりますか?
It concept should be next sentence to avoid repetition
繰り返しを避けるため、コンセプトは次の文にする必要があります
etc.
等
Then I can build my
そうすれば、自分のものを構築できます
audio summary
音声概要
I can show you this later
これは後でお見せできます
example
例
come again
また来てね
I also wish to generate headers
ヘッダーも生成したい
Because the title is easier to click
タイトルをクリックしやすいので
what about the title
タイトルはどうですか
you know
ほら
The characteristic of this title is
このタイトルの特徴は、
it is text
それはテキストです
it should be shorter
もっと短いはずです
but to read
でも読むために
Let me give you an example here
ここで例を挙げてみましょう
The basic way we do headlines
見出しの基本的な作り方
is the voice file
音声ファイルです
I first identify
まず特定します
then make a summary
それから要約を作成します
i by the words inside the abstract
私は要約内の単語によって
Then choose the important words in it
次に、その中から重要な単語を選択します
make a title
タイトルを作る
There are optional words
オプションの単語があります
model with word choice
言葉を選ぶモデル
how to sort words
言葉を並べ替える方法
sorted model
ソートされたモデル
How long should the title have it's model etc
タイトルにモデルなどを含める必要がある長さ
These models use training corpus
これらのモデルはトレーニング コーパスを使用します
trained
訓練された
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
Because I can catch a lot of words written by people on the Internet
インターネット上で人々が書いた言葉をたくさんキャッチできるから
with title in it
タイトルが入っている
someone made the title
誰かがタイトルを付けた
The text I can write about the candidate
候補者について書ける文章
Make headlines with people to train those in the middle
中間層を訓練するために人々の見出しを作る
how to choose words
言葉の選び方
how to sort
並べ替え方法
how does it determine its length etc.
長さなどはどのように決まるのでしょうか。
so I can use this to make the title
これをタイトルに使用できます
This meeting will also show you the real thing
この会議では本物も見せます
come again
また来てね
knowledge structure
知識構造
what is knowledge structure
知識構造とは何ですか
we don't know
私たちは知りません
But let's give two examples
しかし、例を 2 つ挙げましょう
The first example is that we put any
最初の例は、
concept or theme
コンセプトやテーマ
Subdivide the concept or theme of the audio file
音声ファイルのコンセプトやテーマを細分化する
and then arrange it into a two-dimensional vertical structure
それを二次元の垂直構造に配置します
For example, if the concept theme is very similar, turn it into a group of
たとえば、コンセプトのテーマが非常に似ている場合は、それをグループに変換します。
Put a piece inside the two
2つの中にピースを入れます
I tag it with a set of keywords
一連のキーワードでタグ付けします
Let the user know what it is at a glance
ユーザーに一目でそれが何であるかを知らせる
And then, if there are many uniform groups
では、均一なグループが多数あった場合はどうなるでしょうか。
I can go down one more layer and expand and divide into groups and so on.
さらに 1 つ下のレイヤーに移動して展開し、グループなどに分割することができます。
I will show you an example of this later
この例については後ほどお見せします
What's more, I can also make a picture of keywords
さらに、キーワードを画像化することもできます
For example, if I find a bunch of voice files
たとえば、大量の音声ファイルを見つけた場合
I find the keywords for each voice file
各音声ファイルのキーワードを見つけます
Mark it with these key words to mark what it is
それが何であるかを示すために、これらのキーワードをマークしてください
Then what about the relationship between these keywords?
では、これらのキーワードの関係はどうなるのでしょうか？
I can draw a picture to show how they are related
それらがどのように関連しているかを示す絵を描くことができます
This helped me find
これは私が見つけるのに役立ちました
I will show you an example of this later
この例については後ほどお見せします
One last thing to say
最後に一つ言っておきます
There is one more dialogue, how to do the dialogue?
もう 1 つ対話がありますが、どのように対話を行うのですか?
Just assume that the user enters a command
ユーザーがコマンドを入力したと仮定します。
Also looking for the President of the United States
アメリカ大統領も探しています
Then the machine went to find it
それから機械がそれを探しに行きました
As a result, what the President of the United States did
その結果、アメリカ大統領がとった行動は、
a lot of weird
たくさんの奇妙な
very scattered
非常に散らばっている
so that the result is so bad
結果がとても悪いので
The machine knows it's not working
機械は自分が動いていないことを知っている
If this large pile is handed over to the user
この大きな山をユーザーに渡せば
Users are annoyed
ユーザーはイライラしている
So we don't provide this result to the user
したがって、この結果はユーザーには提供されません
Ask the user to say if you can add one more command
もう 1 つコマンドを追加できるかどうかをユーザーに尋ねます
so the user
それでユーザーは
what i want is diplomacy
私が欲しいのは外交です
After having this, the machine will look different again
これを手に入れると、マシンの見た目がまた変わります
He found a lot of things about the president of the United States related to diplomacy
彼はアメリカ大統領について外交に関連した多くのことを見つけた
However, there is a trend
ただし、傾向はあります
That is, many of them are related to the Middle East.
つまり、その多くは中東に関連しています。
Middle East is their keyword
中東が彼らのキーワード
Since this is the case
こういうことなので
but still messy
でもまだ汚い
At this time, the machine can use this keyword
現時点では、マシンはこのキーワードを使用できます
Go to confirm with the user that what you want is the Middle East
あなたが望んでいるのが中東であることをユーザーに確認しに行きます
If this is the user says yes
これが当てはまる場合、ユーザーは「はい」と答えます
right
右
then i can throw all the middle east to it
そうすれば中東全体をそれに投げ込むことができる
Then probably won't die
そしたら多分死なないよ
Or the user says no, what I want is Asia
あるいはユーザーが「いいえ、私が欲しいのはアジアです」と言います。
That's okay, I already know it's Asia.
大丈夫、ここがアジアだということはもうわかっています。
I can search again and find Asia and so on
もう一度検索してアジアなどを見つけることができます
this is called a dialogue
これは対話と呼ばれます
Okay, so I've said everything on the picture just now.
さて、今の写真にあることはすべて言いました。
Here is a summary of the key vocabulary title Knowledge Structure Dialogue
ここでは、重要な語彙タイトル「知識構造対話」の概要を示します。
Alright, most of what I'm going to say today ends here.
さて、今日お話しすることのほとんどはここで終わります。
The last paragraph below is to show you some live demonstrations
以下の最後の段落では、いくつかのライブ デモンストレーションを示します。
We are divided into three levels
3つのレベルに分かれています
a general structure
一般的な構造
one is general knowledge
1つは一般的な知識です
one is professional knowledge
1つは専門的な知識です
one is language learning
一つは語学学習です
Let's look at the first general knowledge part first
まず最初の一般知識の部分を見てみましょう
What we show you is official news
私たちが紹介するのは公式ニュースです
same ok
同じですよ
No, is your system turned on?
いいえ、システムの電源は入っていますか?
turn on the system first
まずシステムの電源を入れてください
The formula news on our side is from 2002 to 2003
当方の公式ニュースは2002年から2003年までです
A total of about 1100 pieces were recorded
合計約1100曲を収録
sorry 6000
ごめんなさい6000
News with a formula of about 110 hours
約110時間分のニュース
make a news system
ニュースシステムを作る
It was done in the spring of 2006
2006年の春に完成しました
So it's an old system from 7 years ago
7年前の古いシステムなので
We didn't put it online at the time
当時はオンラインに公開していませんでした
only in one machine
1台のマシンのみで
So we still bring that machine to repair today for everyone to see
それで私たちは今日もその機械を修理に持ち込んで、誰もが見ることができるようにしています
So it's a comparison
ということで比較です
OK
OK
minimize it first
まずは最小化する
OK good
いいよ
OK, let's take a look now
さて、それでは見てみましょう
what i'm going to say now is this is this
私が今言おうとしているのはこれです
first general knowledge
最初の一般知識
Our example is TV news
私たちの例はテレビのニュースです
So let's think about what TV news is like
テレビのニュースがどのようなものかを考えてみましょう
basically it probably contains no text
基本的にはテキストが含まれていない可能性があります
Then its themes are very diverse
それからそのテーマは非常に多様です
So the group title we just said
それで、先ほど言ったグループタイトルは
Keywords are helpful for browsing
キーワードは閲覧に役立ちます
it's not easy to recognize
認識するのは簡単ではありません
Because there are so many new words
新しい単語がたくさんあるので、
But for most news
しかし、ほとんどのニュースでは
Most users don't need to know that detailed
ほとんどのユーザーはそこまで詳しく知る必要はありません
So cheating on the title is helpful
タイトルを騙すのは役に立ちます
The information of each news itself is complete
各ニュースの情報自体は充実している
Listen to news without additional information
追加情報なしでニュースを聞く
So the purpose of the knowledge structure is to assist browsing
したがって、知識構造の目的はブラウジングを支援することです。
Okay, let's look at the part just now
さて、今の部分を見てみましょう
Let's show you a TV news first
まずはテレビニュースをお見せしましょう
you can find out
あなたは知ることができます
The voice signal of this formula news is below
この公式ニュースの音声信号は以下です
You see the full length is more than 1 minute and 40 seconds
全長が 1 分 40 秒を超えていることがわかります。
Then we have this in sync
これで同期が取れました
The picture is also drawn here
ここにも絵が描かれています
We can listen once to know what it's talking about
一度聞いて、何について話しているのかを知ることができます
Southwest Airlines has a Boeing 737
サウスウエスト航空はボーイング737を持っています
When flying from Baltimore to Chicago
ボルチモアからシカゴへご出発の場合
On landing in a blizzard
吹雪の中の着陸時
overshot the runway and the airport fence
滑走路と空港のフェンスを越えた
It hit two cars on the road
道路上の車2台に衝突した
At that time, after the chicken blood was beaten to 18 centimeters
当時、鶏の血を18センチまで叩いた後、
Is the plane under surveillance because it ran too slippery?
滑走しすぎたので飛行機は監視されているのだろうか？
Authorities are still investigating
当局はまだ捜査を続けている
Chicago Airport 33 years ago
33年前のシカゴ空港
There has also been a major crash
大規模な事故も起きた
are all in the result radio
すべて結果ラジオにあります
Kashiba GG
香芝GG
I can speed up
スピードアップできるよ
but can follow the master tape
ただしマスターテープを追うことはできる
this three-letter sound
この三文字の音
no translation
一語不译
then we are not good
それなら私たちはダメだ
as long as we are
私たちがいる限り
understand that is a
それは理解してください
only a few places
ほんの数か所だけ
1 times the word today Haven
今日の単語を 1 倍ヘイブン
Already counted
すでにカウントされています
I see this Tongiting La Viet
トンギティン・ラ・ヴィエットが見えます
Runway and airport fence results
滑走路と空港フェンスの結果
Collide
衝突する
put two cars on the road
車を2台道路に置く
One dead, eleven wounded
1名が死亡、11名が負傷
Chicago International Airport in the midst of an out-of-air accident
シカゴ国際空港、機外事故の真っ只中
still snowing
まだ雪が降っています
Fire trucks and ambulances rushed to the scene immediately
消防車と救急車がすぐに現場に急行しました
But the university keeps going
でも大学は進み続ける
It also increases the difficulty of rescue
救助の難易度も上がる
The accident happened at local time
事故は現地時間に発生した
7:15pm on the 8th
8日午後7時15分
Southwest Airlines had 103 passengers on board
サウスウエスト航空には103人の乗客が搭乗していた
Active Crew Boeing Air Fan Airliner
アクティブクルー ボーイング エアファン旅客機
Flying from Baltimore to Chicago Airport
ボルチモア発シカゴ空港行きのフライト
Suspected because of bad weather
悪天候のため疑われている
Winning off the runway and forming a strong knot
滑走路を勝ち取り、強い結び目を形成する
Hit two cars on the road
道路上の2台の車に衝突する
One of them got stuck under the plane
そのうちの1人が飛行機の下敷きになった
6-year-old boy dies in car
6歳男児が車ではねられ死亡
Eleven people on board and on the ground were injured
船上および地上の11人が負傷した
The plane itself was also involved in the collision
飛行機自体も衝突に巻き込まれた
Damaged the nose and dropped a Secret
機首を傷つけてシークレットを落とした
Eyewitnesses described the situation
目撃者は状況を説明した
The airport staff pointed out that when the snow reached 18 centimeters,
空港職員は、雪が18センチに達したとき、
Did this plane create momentum because it flew to Taihua?
この飛行機は太華に飛んだので勢いがついたのでしょうか？
Authorities are still investigating
当局はまだ捜査を続けている
33 years ago, there was one at the Chicago airport.
33年前、シカゴ空港にもありました。
major crash accident
大衝突事故
45 people left
残り45名
On this plane, airport personnel at the time noted that
この飛行機について、当時の空港職員は次のように述べています。
The airport staff at the time pointed out that
当時の空港職員はこう指摘した。
45 people left
残り45名
Fruit News This Meeting Variation
フルーツニュース この会議のバリエーション
This is more than 1 minute and 40 seconds of news
1分40秒以上のニュースです
Everyone, just saw
皆さん、今見ましたよ
let's see again
もう一度見てみましょう
How did we extract the summary?
要約をどのように抽出したのでしょうか?
Just find these two sentences in it
その中でこの 2 つの文を見つけてください
this red sentence
この赤い文
with this red line
赤い線で
These two sentences are the most important sentences
この 2 つの文は最も重要な文です
wrap it up
急いでください
Almost the most important part of the full text
全文のほぼ最も重要な部分
we call it a summary
私たちはそれを要約と呼びます
These two add up to 19 seconds
これら 2 つを合計すると 19 秒になります
What about the picture?
絵はどうですか？
we need another team
別のチームが必要だ
Help us draw important pictures
大切な絵を描くのを手伝ってください
It is based on the message of the screen
画面のメッセージに基づく
For example, someone's face is moving
たとえば、誰かの顔が動いているとします。
changed face
顔が変わった
or this thing that's moving
またはこれが動いているもの
is the important thing
重要なことです
They also add up to 19 seconds in this way
この方法では最大 19 秒も加算されます
So get a 19 second pick
だから19秒指名権を獲得する
let's see it again now
今もう一度見てみましょう
Southwest Airlines has a Boeing 737
サウスウエスト航空はボーイング737を持っています
When flying from Faltimore to Chicago
ファルティモアからシカゴまでごフライトの場合
blizzard on landing
着陸時の吹雪
overshot the runway and the airport fence
滑走路と空港のフェンスを越えた
It hit two cars on the road
道路上の車2台に衝突した
When the snow reached 18 centimeters
積雪が18センチになった頃
Is this plane making a fuss about being too slippery?
この飛行機は滑りやすいと騒いでいるのでしょうか？
Authorities are still investigating
当局はまだ捜査を続けている
Chicago Airport 33 years ago
33年前のシカゴ空港
There was also a major crash
大事故もあったし
you can see
見ることができます
last sentence
最後の文
It is different from the previous sentence
前の文と違います
There are a lot of things in this
この中にはたくさんのものが入っています
In fact, the previous sentence already exists
実際、前の文はすでに存在します
so no more
だからもうだめだ
etc.
等
This is already taken
これはすでに取られています
we just said
私たちは今言いました
Actually, I can make the title
実はタイトルも作れるんです
Let's show you below
以下でお見せしましょう
This is a title made by a computer
これはコンピューターで作られたタイトルです
then you can initiate
それから始めることができます
Whether it is the title or the abstract of this computer
このコンピュータのタイトルか要約か
Of course no one does it well
もちろん上手くできる人はいない
this man must do better
この人はもっと頑張らなければならない
But our point is not that he wants to compare with others
しかし、私たちが言いたいのは、彼が他人と比較したいということではありません
but after having these things
しかし、これらのものを持った後
can help us browse
ブラウジングに役立ちます
Then sometimes I don't have to listen to the end
そうすると最後まで聞かなくてもいいこともある
And I saw his title
そして彼のタイトルを見ました
listen to his abstract
彼の要約を聞いてください
I know that, do I still want to listen?
それはわかっていますが、それでも聞きたいですか？
I really want to hear me go play the full thing
フルで演奏してもらいたいです
on the line
ライン上で
You may think
と思うかも知れません
You may have picked the best sentence for this one.
あなたはこの文に最適な文を選んだかもしれません。
come to this show
この番組に来てください
that's not true
それは真実ではない
I just said that our system
私はちょうど私たちのシステムを言いました
What's inside is
中にあるのは、
PTV News in 2002 to 2003
2002 年から 2003 年の PTV ニュース
a total of one hundred and ten hours
合計111時間
One hundred and ten hours six thousand
111時間6000
Every news does what it just did
どのニュースもまさにそれがやったことをやっている
Then make a system like this
じゃあこんなシステムを作ります
That
それか
Katamin Ecstasy
カタミンエクスタシー
or mahiro
まひろとか
Suoying, various types of bottles, Department of Health today
Suoying、さまざまな種類のボトル、今日の保健省
This is the news we usually see when we go home and turn on the TV
これは私たちが家に帰ってテレビをつけるとよく見るニュースです
Then I don't want to hear 80% of the news he tells.
そうなると、彼が語るニュースの80％は聞きたくない。
But turning around, there's nothing I want to hear
でも振り向いたら聞きたいことなんて何もない
So we want a formula like this
したがって、次のような式が必要です
such a news system
そんなニュースシステム
The first one I put all received news
最初に受け取ったニュースをすべて入れます
made his abstract and title respectively
それぞれ要約とタイトルを作成しました
Abstract here Title here
要旨はこちら タイトルはこちら
Then I divide all the news into these six categories
次に、すべてのニュースを次の 6 つのカテゴリに分類します
International Politics, Finance, etc.
国際政治、金融など
According to his content, it's all made by machines
彼の内容によれば、すべて機械で作られているという。
Then my homepage is the one for each type of news
そうすると、私のホームページはそれぞれの種類のニュースのホームページになります
The most recent one is presented with his title
最新のものは彼のタイトルで表示されます
Users can see if I want
ユーザーは必要に応じて見ることができます
If you want, click him to get the complete news
必要に応じて、彼をクリックして完全なニュースを入手してください
Click on the summary and I will hear the summary
概要をクリックすると概要を聞きます
Of course, this, this, each of these may be
もちろん、これも、これも、それぞれかもしれません
not what i want to see
私が見たいものではありません
then i can choose
それなら私は選ぶことができます
Let's say I just want to watch international news
国際ニュースを見たいだけだとしましょう
Well there's a whole lot of international news here
さて、ここには国際的なニュースがたくさんあります
Then I can watch political news, financial news, etc.
そうすれば、政治ニュースや経済ニュースなどを見ることができます。
even if that's the case
たとえそうだとしても
There may be more international news
もっと国際的なニュースがあるかもしれません
you see so much international news
国際的なニュースをたくさん見ますね
Still hard to choose
まだ選ぶのが難しい
What should we do then?
それでは何をすべきでしょうか？
I can click on this bird to see the picture
この鳥をクリックすると写真が見られます
The picture of this bird is what we just saw
この鳥の写真は私たちが今見たものです
is my analysis of news according to the vocabulary of its content
内容の語彙に基づいてニュースを分析したものです
I will divide it into nine categories
９つに分類してみます
Of course each category is
もちろんそれぞれのカテゴリーは
computer doesn't know
コンピューターは知りません
but what about each category
しかし、それぞれのカテゴリーはどうなるのでしょうか
i can smoke it keywords
吸ってもいいです キーワード
or key phrase
またはキーフレーズ
after pulling out
抜いた後
make it the most important keyword
それを最も重要なキーワードにします
The highest score is listed here
最高スコアはここに表示されます
Let's see
どれどれ
You can probably see what it is
おそらくそれが何であるかがわかるでしょう
For example
例えば
what is this
これは何ですか
There were planes, explosions, and earthquakes
飛行機、爆発、地震がありました
It's all kinds of natural and man-made disasters
それはあらゆる種類の自然災害と人為的災害です
what is this
これは何ですか
Another Ministry of Health, another whale, another case
別の保健省、別のクジラ、別の事件
I know this should be a health problem for the whole world
これは全世界にとって健康上の問題であるはずだと私は知っています
with disease
病気で
This is a chair-tooth dispute in the Middle East
これは中東における椅子の歯の紛争です
This is North and South Korea and so on
ここは北朝鮮と韓国などです
It can be seen that the Overseas Bridge is full, etc.
オーヴァーシーズブリッジが満杯になっていることがわかります。
That's a little weird
それはちょっと変だ
like nothing
何もないように
We later found out that this is
後でわかったことですが、これは
none of above
以上皆非
In other words, all the news we had at the time
言い換えれば、当時私たちが知っていたすべてのニュースは、
It can be roughly divided into these eight categories
大きく分けてこの8つに分類できます
There is a category that is really nothing
何もないカテゴリがあります
called none of the above
上記のどれとも呼ばれない
Let's say I want to watch all kinds of natural and man-made disasters
あらゆる種類の自然災害と人為的災害を見たいとしましょう
I can go in from here
ここから入ることができます
i get the next layer
次のレイヤーを取得します
We just saw two-dimensional structures
二次元構造を見たばかりです
This layer expands it to nine
このレイヤーは9つに拡張します
This natural and man-made disaster can be divided into
この自然災害と人災は次のように分類できます。
Let's say it's a homicide
殺人事件だとしましょう
this is the plane that crashed
これは墜落した飛行機です
volcanic earthquake tsunami
火山性地震 津波
you say it's weird
あなたはそれが奇妙だと言います
Why do tsunamis and volcanoes go together
津波と火山はなぜ起こるのか
because they use similar words
似たような言葉を使っているので
For example, this hurricane will be with heavy snow
たとえば、今回のハリケーンは大雪を伴うでしょう
It is also a similar relationship between the words used
使われている言葉の間でも同様の関係があります
may not find
見つからないかもしれない
This strike is also a disaster
今回のストライキも大惨事だ
because he used words like
彼は次のような言葉を使ったからです
For example, road section or traffic impassability
たとえば、道路区間や通行不能など
So the word used is like
したがって、使用される単語は次のようなものです
How do you say this teenager is also
このティーンエイジャーも何と言いますか？
because he was a riot and so on
彼は暴動を起こしていたからなど
So if you want to know about this teenager's disaster
このティーンエイジャーの災害について知りたいのであれば
Scourge or something
スカージか何か
you click in to see
クリックして見ると
that's what he's talking about
それが彼が話していることです
then we can
それならできます
Because I only have two layers in total now
今は合計 2 つのレイヤーしかないので、
In fact, this can be many layers
実際には、これは多くの層になる可能性があります
But now because there is not much news about this
しかし、今はこの件に関するニュースがあまりないので、
So a total of two layers
つまり合計2層になります
So by now it's bottom
だから今は最下位だよ
all of his
彼のすべて
There are many more news like that listed here
他にも同様のニュースがここにリストされています
etc.
等
Then we can see for example
次に、たとえば、
what is this one about
これは何についてですか
I can click in and have a look
クリックして見てみることができます
12 days of riots in France
フランスで12日間続く暴動
On the evening of the 7th in Paris and Toulouse
7日の夜、パリとトゥールーズで
Become again
またなる
You probably know what he's talking about
あなたはおそらく彼が何について話しているのか知っているでしょう
The title is sometimes weird
タイトルがたまに変だけど
but you probably know what he's talking about
しかし、あなたはおそらく彼が何について話しているのか知っているでしょう
This is another one, let's click in and have a look
これはもう 1 つです。クリックして見てみましょう
The violent riots continued, and the sudden golden boy set fire on the street in the early morning of the 14th
暴動は続き、１４日早朝、突然ゴールデンボーイが路上に放火した。
Wait, this browsing we call Top Down
待ってください、このブラウジングを私たちはトップダウンと呼んでいます
because you're looking down from the top of the tree
木の上から見下ろしているから
Of course, I can do it the other way around.
もちろん、その逆もできます。
Battle Nights Looking Up from the Bottom
下から見上げるバトルナイト
If I go back to the main screen
メイン画面に戻ると
Let's say I'm here looking for international news
国際ニュースを探しにここにいるとしましょう
I look down from here
ここから見下ろします
Suppose I see a certain news
あるニュースを見たとします。
For example, the Iraqi election bombing, I want to see this one
例えばイラク選挙爆破事件、これを見たい。
I'll just click in and see
クリックして見てみましょう
Eight big polling places just opened their doors
8つの大きな投票所がオープンしたばかり
let voters vote
有権者に投票してもらいましょう
There was a loud bang in the green zone
グリーンゾーンで大きな音がした
Suppose I see this one, when I finish this one,
これを見たとしましょう、これが終わったら、
I feel like I want to know more news
もっとニュースを知りたい気分です
I can click related news
関連ニュースをクリックできます
related news
関連ニュース
It took me to that spot in its tree
それは私をその木のあの場所に連れて行ってくれました
just here
ここだけ
These are all about the Iraqi bombings, right?
これらはすべてイラク爆撃に関するものですよね？
related news
関連ニュース
then i can do more
そうすればもっとできるよ
I listen to the news here
ここでニュースを聞きます
I can also go up one level
一つレベルアップすることもできる
just get
ただ手に入れるだけ
i am here now
今ここにいる
It's eight brains exploding and so on.
8つの脳が爆発するなどです。
that belongs to this block
このブロックに属するもの
I'm on the upper floor
私は上の階にいます
I will go back to the part of natural disaster characters and wait.
自然災害の登場人物のパートに戻って待ちます。
This is where the guaranteed bottom-up search
ここでボトムアップ検索が保証されます
of course
もちろん
I can actually find something else
実は他のものを見つけることができます
For example
例えば
If I go back to the main screen
メイン画面に戻ると
I can actually do the search directly
実際に直接検索することもできます
In our case it is called retrieval
私たちの場合、それは検索と呼ばれます
let's try
やってみよう
is it possible
出来ますか
ok
Ok
good
良い
let's try
やってみよう
I will retest
再テストします
try mute
ミュートしてみる
Okay, now I should be able to go in with my voice.
よし、これで声を出して入ることができるはずだ。
so what
だから何
try again
再試行する
then let's try
それでは試してみましょう
Please help me find the White House
ホワイトハウスを見つけるのを手伝ってください
It doesn't seem to go in. Let's do it again.
入らないようです。もう一度やりましょう。
good
良い
I want him not working now
彼には今は働かないでほしい
Please help me find the White House
ホワイトハウスを見つけるのを手伝ってください
He changed the environment, it seems
環境を変えたらしい
is such a relationship
そういう関係ですか
OK, let's try again, that's right.
OK、もう一度試してみましょう、そうです。
ok ok one more time
わかりました、もう一度
OK, please help me find the White House
オーケー、ホワイトハウスを見つけるのを手伝ってください
No, still not
いいえ、まだです
Should be a little better. Let's do it again.
もう少し良くなるはずです。もう一度やりましょう。
Please help me find the White House
ホワイトハウスを見つけるのを手伝ってください
Got it, got it, OK
わかりました
According to the New York Times report
ニューヨークタイムズの報道によると
Senior U.S. intelligence agent from Itain, Iran
イラン・イテイン出身の米国上級諜報員
Emergencies of practice in computer
コンピュータ実習の緊急事態
Discover more than 1000 pages of computer patterns
1000 ページを超えるコンピューター パターンを発見
Strong selling shopping channel no matter what
何があっても販売力の高いショッピング チャネル
well what we just saw
さて、私たちが今見たもの
it moved
動いた
this
これ
ok i think u can make this
わかりました、これは作れると思います
This is what I just said was completed in 2006, 7 years ago
これは先ほど言ったもので、7年前の2006年に完成したものです。
So inevitably I'm talking now and he's going in
だから必然的に私が今話していると彼は入ってしまう
so he keeps finding something else
だから彼は何か他のものを見つけ続ける
he found something different now
彼は今何か違うものを見つけた
OK, what about our part?
さて、私たちの側はどうでしょうか？
we'll stop here
ここでやめます
Let's go back to the main screen
メイン画面に戻りましょう
Then I leave here too
じゃあ、私もここを離れます
Okay, I was talking about the TV news.
さて、テレビのニュースについて話していました。
Let's look at the second one, which is professional knowledge
2 つ目は専門的な知識です。
What about specialized knowledge? A good example
専門知識についてはどうでしょうか? 良い例
online course
オンラインコース
What about online courses, you can download
オンラインコースはどうですか？ダウンロードできます
Imagine that there are so many online courses today
今日、非常に多くのオンラインコースがあることを想像してみてください
But you often take a long time
でも、長い時間がかかることが多いです
in order to fully learn
完全に学ぶために
For example, a 45-hour essay class
たとえば、45時間のエッセイクラス
It is difficult for a busy person to listen carefully for 45 hours
忙しい人にとって45時間じっくり聞くのは難しい
so what can we do
それで、私たちは何ができるでしょうか
real online courses
本物のオンラインコース
is searchable by a browser
ブラウザで検索可能です
for example
例えば
which one are you looking for
どれを探していますか
just go find that part, you can find it
その部分を探しに行ってください、あなたはそれを見つけることができます
the problem is to say
問題はそれです
The course is structured
コースは構成されています
You learn the former to understand the latter
後者を理解するために前者を学ぶ
Then if you search for a piece of content you want to know
知りたい内容を検索すると
but you haven't heard before
でもあなたは今まで聞いたことがない
maybe you don't understand
たぶんあなたは理解していません
then i don't know the background
それでは背景が分かりません
But I don't know how to find their relevant knowledge
しかし、関連する知識を見つける方法がわかりません
I don't know what else to look for
他に何を探せばいいのか分かりません
because of this relationship
この関係のせいで
We just want to do an online course
オンラインコースをやりたいだけです
But it is intellectually structured
しかしそれは知的に構造化されている
This knowledge structure is what we just said
この知識構造は先ほど述べたものです
But we use another thing
しかし、私たちは別のものを使います
Online courses often have auxiliary slides
オンライン コースには補助スライドが含まれることがよくあります
we use auxiliary
私たちは補助的に使用します
slideshow to do it
それを行うためのスライドショー
For example
例えば
I can join the meeting with a slideshow and its key
スライドショーとそのキーを使用して会議に参加できます
to build knowledge structure
知識構造を構築する
I put the entire course content
コース内容をすべて載せます
in slides
スライドで
Each slide is cut into a small segment
各スライドは小さなセグメントにカットされます
Each subsection is represented by its key
各サブセクションはそのキーによって表されます
as the core of knowledge
知識の核として
So I can put these keys in the meeting
これで会議にこれらの鍵を置くことができます
Draw a picture to describe the relationship between them
それらの関係を説明するために絵を描いてください
So each of my clips of slides
私のスライドの各クリップは
while providing a wealth of knowledge
豊富な知識を提供しながら
For example, how long is it?
例えばどれくらいですか？
you want to see how long it is
どのくらいの長さか知りたいですか
Then what are the key participants
では、主要な参加者は誰ですか
What are the relevant key participants
関連する主な参加者は誰ですか
What are the other related slides etc.
他に関連するスライドなどは何ですか。
This helps users click to browse
これにより、ユーザーがクリックして閲覧できるようになります
If you do a search and find the statement
検索してその記述を見つけたら
I also provide snippets of slideshows that belong
に属するスライドショーのスニペットも提供します
and its related information
およびその関連情報
to help users click through
ユーザーがクリックスルーできるようにするため
for example
例えば
This is what we show you below
これは以下でご紹介するものです
this is a class
これはクラスです
This class is my class
このクラスは私のクラスです
digital voice processing
デジタル音声処理
The content of this course is bilingual in Chinese and English
このコースの内容は中国語と英語のバイリンガルです
That is to say, my lectures are taught in Chinese
つまり、私の講義は中国語で行われます
But all the professional numbers in it
しかし、そこにはプロの数字がすべて含まれています
It's all in English and not translated into Chinese
すべて英語で、中国語には翻訳されていません
So it's a mixture of Chinese and English
つまり中国語と英語の混合です
and spontaneous speech
そして自発的なスピーチ
Which means I didn't read it from the script.
つまり、台本から読んでいないということです。
I watched the slide show in class
授業中にスライドショーを見ました
just wait
ちょっと待って
such a signal
そのような信号
So let's look at such a system
それでは、そのようなシステムを見てみましょう
We are called NTU Virtual Teachers
私たちは NTU バーチャルティーチャーと呼ばれています
this is his website
これは彼のウェブサイトです
this is on the website
これはウェブサイトにあります
So we're now connecting directly through the network
したがって、現在はネットワーク経由で直接接続しています
link to that site
そのサイトへのリンク
this is my class
これは私のクラスです
digital voice processing
デジタル音声処理
So this one was recorded in 2006
つまりこれは2006年に録音されたものです
So it was also
それもそうだった
It was recorded seven years ago
7年前に録音したものです
This was done in 2009
これは2009年に行われました
So it's four years old
それで4歳になりました
we just said
私たちは今言いました
We just divide it according to the slides
スライドに従って分割するだけです
for example
例えば
This is the first one
これが最初のものです
each
各
first slide
最初のスライド
second slide
2番目のスライド
etc.
等
Let's say I order the fourth slide
4 番目のスライドを注文したとしましょう
I think this is the fourth slide
これが 4 番目のスライドだと思います
etc.
等
I can also watch the next slide here
次のスライドもここで見ることができます
previous slide
前のスライド
this is fine
これは大丈夫です
He told me a bunch of info here
彼はここでたくさんの情報を教えてくれました
For example
例えば
this slide
このスライド
It took a total of three minutes and 44 seconds to finish the speech
演説を終えるまでに合計3分44秒かかった
His position is in the first of eighteen
彼の順位は18位中1位です
This slideshow of him in the first one
最初の彼のスライドショー
above wait
待ってください
I can also say for example
例えばこんなことも言えます
come back
戻ってくる
i choose one
私は一つを選びます
For example, the seventh
たとえば、7 番目の
i can watch
見ることができます
For example, in the seventh
たとえば、7番目では、
a certain slide
とあるスライド
for example this
たとえばこれ
This is his sixth slide
これは彼の 6 番目のスライドです
It's his eighth slide, etc.
それは彼の 8 番目のスライドなどです。
Then I can also see that
そうすると、それもわかります
in my slide
私のスライドでは
He said the full length of the slideshow is 2 minutes and 30 seconds
スライドショーの全長は 2 分 30 秒であると彼は言いました
He has a 15 second sample
彼は 15 秒のサンプルを持っています
Then let me listen to this 15 second sample
それでは、この 15 秒のサンプルを聞いてみましょう
click down
クリックダウン
i can hear it all
全部聞こえるよ
we listen to a 15 second sample of his
彼の 15 秒のサンプルを聴きます
Hope this network can work
このネットワークが機能することを願っています
Therefore the higher frequency part
したがって、高周波部分は
the fainter the less clear
暗くなるほど不鮮明になる
then we'll pull it up a bit
それから少し引き上げます
So let's compare the sensitive feeling
では、その敏感な感覚を比べてみましょう
can feel it here
ここでそれを感じることができます
That's what we're talking about here
それがここで話していることです
This preemphasis is a basic statement that it is pulling up
この前置きは、引き上げているという基本的な声明です。
That's the 15 minute pill
それは15分の錠剤です
The title of my slide is pre-emphasis
私のスライドのタイトルは強調されています
Then take the medicine in 15 seconds
15秒以内に薬を飲んでください
i can listen to all the wait
待っている間ずっと聞くことができます
Of course I can also search
もちろん検索もできますよ
We can look here to search
ここで検索できます
For example, let's say where I am listening to a lecture
たとえば、どこで講義を聞いているとします。
I also heard someone say that it looks like a Blackbird Algo
Blackbird Algo に似ているという意見も聞きました。
what
何
is it in here
ここにありますか
I'll look for it
探してみます
so i clicked it in
それでクリックしました
let me do a search
検索させてください
it tells me right away
それはすぐに教えてくれます
The entire course is 45 hours
全コースは45時間です
A total of 56 talks about
合計 56 件のトーク
Blackbird Algo you typed
入力した Blackbird アルゴ
But in fact, if you look closely, you will find
しかし、実際によく見てみると、
Actually what's in it
実際には何が入っているのか
Is Blackbird Algo
ブラックバードアルゴですか
That's it
それでおしまい
I'm not actually
実際にはそうではありません
from identified words
認識された単語から
word recognition
単語認識
I'm not looking for words
言葉を求めているわけではない
Because I typed Blackbird Algo
Blackbird Algo と入力したため
But what I found was Blackbird Algo
でも私が見つけたのは Blackbird Algo でした
But I found it by the sound
でも音で見つけた
Because this sound is exactly like this sound
この音はまさにこの音に似ているから
I'm looking for the sound
音を探している
He said you gotta find the BlackWare Algox
彼は BlackWare Algox を見つけなければならないと言った
A total of 56 occurrences
合計 56 回の発生
Every time it's kind of like Google's page
毎回Googleのページのようになる
For example, this is the first time that this sentence is 8 seconds long
たとえば、この文の長さが 8 秒になるのは初めてです。
It's in the slideshow on page 12 of Chapter 4
第 4 章の 12 ページのスライドショーにあります。
You can just listen to these 8 seconds
この8秒だけ聞いてください
I want to hear the whole of this too
これも全部聞きたい
etc.
等
But if you want to listen for only 8 seconds
でも8秒だけ聞きたいなら
probably can't hear anything
おそらく何も聞こえない
Usually we recommend
通常、お勧めします
Should be listening to the whole slideshow
スライドショー全体を聞くべきです
Can I listen to the whole slideshow?
スライドショー全体を聞くことはできますか?
he will tell me
彼は私に教えてくれるでしょう
What are the key words of this slideshow
このスライドショーのキーワードは何ですか
With BlackWare Algox
BlackWare Algox を使用する場合
Etc., etc
などなど
this is his keyword
これが彼のキーワードです
So I can judge based on this
なのでこれを踏まえて判断すればいいのですが
do i listen to him
彼の言うことを聞きますか
Let's say I choose to say I'm coming to hear
話を聞きに来ると言うことにしたとしましょう
I can just click in
クリックするだけです
I should basically get that page
基本的にそのページを取得する必要があります
didn't you give it to me
私にくれませんでしたか？
I'll try this and see if it works
これを試してうまくいくか確認してみます
It doesn't have it. I'm sorry. I don't know why.
それはありません、ごめんなさい、理由はわかりません
let's pick another
別のものを選びましょう
I think there is something wrong with the network
ネットワークに問題があると思います
With that, this is chapter 12
ということで、第12章です
Slideshow
スライドショー
inside this one
この中に
he told me
彼は私に言った
this slide
このスライド
if you want to listen
聞きたいなら
there are 22 minutes
22分あります
he's in the fourth place
彼は4位です
position in all
全体の中での位置
The position of this one in the fourth one
4番目のこれの位置
it's here
ここにあります
you can listen to all
全部聞くことができます
You can also listen to gossip
噂話も聞けます
at the same time is important
同時に重要です
he told me
彼は私に言った
what is his keyword
彼のキーワードは何ですか
Other keywords include EM
他のキーワードにはEMが含まれます
Include the delta here
ここにデルタを含めます
Including backword, elkism, etc.
裏話、エルキズムなどを含む。
Here it says
ここにこう書いてあります
above these are
これらの上には
Keywords for this slideshow
このスライドショーのキーワード
The bottom is with this keyword
下はこのキーワードです
Related keywords are below
関連キーワードは以下
This is not only in this page
このページに限ったことではありませんが、
maybe the whole class
たぶんクラス全員
Related keywords are below
関連キーワードは以下
so i can go down there
だから私はそこに行くことができます
for example
例えば
It should be down here
ここの下にあるはずだ
Why can't I go down?
なぜ下がれないのですか？
how do i go down a bit
少し下がるにはどうすればいいですか
Here are the positions where I want to show my keywords
キーワードを表示したい位置は次のとおりです
The screen is too small, right?
画面が小さすぎますよね？
ok, I have to use the explanation
わかりました、説明を使わなければなりません
But actually I have it here
でも実はここにあるんです
For example, I know
たとえば、私は知っています
i can click
クリックできます
for example
例えば
What I want to see now is this keyword
今見たいのはこのキーワード
forward algorithm
順方向アルゴリズム
I just click
ただクリックするだけです
That's right. That's it.
そうです、それだけです。
it just told me
それは私に言ったばかりです
you are looking for this keyword
このキーワードを探しています
It first appears in Chapter 4 of the
初登場は第4章。
Chapter 12 Inside the same slice
第12章 同一スライス内
Second will appear in these
2番目はこれらに表示されます
so you need to know what it is
だからそれが何なのかを知る必要がある
if you don't know
知らないなら
maybe start listening here
ここから聞き始めるかもしれません
then listen to these
それからこれらを聞いてください
you talk about this now
あなたは今このことについて話しています
should know
知っておくべき
So this is the relationship between these keywords
これらのキーワードの関係は次のとおりです
We should have drawn keywords into a picture
キーワードを絵の中に描くべきだった
But then no drawing
でもその後は絵が描かれない
Because this picture is too complicated
この図は複雑すぎるため、
So which keywords are related to each keyword
では、各キーワードにどのキーワードが関連しているのか
We'll just write it right here
ここにだけ書きます
For example, this is the Begger Algor
たとえば、これは Begger Algor です
if i click in
クリックしたら
I'll tell me
教えてあげる
This Begger Algor first appeared here
この Begger Algor はここで最初に登場しました
and then second appear inside these
次に、これらの中に 2 番目に表示されます
I want to listen to the first time should start here
初めて聴きたいならここから始めましょう
I can go in from here
ここから入ることができます
then here comes this one
それからこれが来ます
I can just go in here and wait
ここに入って待っていてもいいよ
So I get a knowledge structure of the whole course
これでコース全体の知識構造が得られました
Make it easier for users to find what you want
ユーザーが必要なものを見つけやすくする
good
良い
This is our second display
今回は2回目のプレゼンテーションです
third display
3番目のディスプレイ
we're talking about language learning
私たちは言語学習について話しています
What we're showing you is a virtual language tutor
私たちが紹介しているのは仮想言語家庭教師です
What about this we can imagine
これについてはどうなるでしょうか
Language learning is increasingly important
言語学習の重要性はますます高まっています
Because we are a globalized world
グローバル化した世界だから
Everyone needs a language other than his mother tongue to help him
誰もが自分を助けるために母語以外の言語を必要としています
But when learning a language other than your mother tongue
しかし、母語以外の言語を学ぶ場合、
A bunch of additional teaching is the most effective but expensive
追加の教育をたくさん行うのが最も効果的ですが、費用がかかります
So therefore we feel that
したがって、私たちは次のように感じています
You can let the computer take over the role of this pile of tutoring
この山積みの個別指導の役割をコンピュータに引き継がせることができます
Computers are not as good as humans
コンピュータは人間ほど優秀ではない
But the biggest advantage is
しかし、最大の利点は、
It can be used countless times anytime, anywhere
いつでもどこでも何度でも使えます
it doesn't get angry and doesn't rest
怒らないし休まない
hard work
大変な仕事
based on that
それに基づいて
Computers can win
コンピュータは勝てる
Of course we are not saying that computers are going to replace teachers
もちろん、コンピュータが教師に取って代わると言っているわけではありません。
is impossible
不可能です
But a language teacher can use this software
ただし、語学教師はこのソフトウェアを使用できます
To teach a large group of students many classes at the same time
大人数のグループに同時に多くのクラスを教えるには
We can also have online schools
オンラインスクールもできます
There are social networks for learners, etc.
学習者向けのソーシャルネットワークなどがあります。
Okay, so the one I'm showing you is Chinese from National Taiwan University.
さて、私が紹介しているのは国立台湾大学の中国人です。
software for learning chinese
中国語を学習するためのソフトウェア
teaching foreigners to learn Chinese
外国人に中国語を教える
what's in there
そこには何がありますか
The main content is
主な内容は、
Various most important communication functions
最も重要なさまざまな通信機能
including greetings
挨拶も含めて
ask
聞く
invite, wait
招待して、待ってください
every communication function
あらゆる通信機能
we have basic sentences
基本的な文があります
different application scenarios
さまざまなアプリケーションシナリオ
For example, people, facts, places, etc.
たとえば、人物、事実、場所などです。
Then what
じゃあ何
It can contain all pronunciation units
すべての発音単位を含めることができます
and this change in tone
そしてこの口調の変化
it can contain
含むことができます
Most of the basic common words
基本的な一般的な単語のほとんど
from easy to difficult
簡単なものから難しいものまで
Then what
じゃあ何
Consider actual language learning needs
実際の言語学習のニーズを考慮する
then this is
それならこれは
Our Chinese teacher at the Liberal Arts College of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学教養学院の中国語教師
Help us design course content
コースコンテンツのデザインにご協力ください
good
良い
what's down there
そこには何がありますか
I can show you this National Taiwan University Mandarin
この国立台湾大学中国語をお見せします
This is the Chinese website of National Taiwan University
こちらは国立台湾大学の中国語ウェブサイトです
There are 12 units in total
全部で12ユニットあります
That is, the 12 communication functions are written here
つまり、12の通信機能がここに書かれています
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
Let's look at this praise and response
この賞賛と反応を見てみましょう
how do i order this
これはどうやって注文すればいいですか
ok
Ok
then which one do i order
じゃあどれを注文しようか
this is
これは
then come back here
それからここに戻ってきてください
ok good
いいよ
This is a compliment response
これは褒め言葉です
We have the basic shape and the applied shape
基本形状と応用形状をご用意しております
let's see one
一つ見てみましょう
For example, in the basic form, there are
たとえば、基本的な形式には次のものがあります。
e.g. grade response
例: 成績評価
What is graded response?
段階的応答とは何ですか?
let's take a look
見てみましょう
when people praise
人が褒めるとき
Are you accepting compliments?
あなたは褒め言葉を受け入れていますか？
Or accept compliments politely?
それとも褒め言葉を丁寧に受け取りますか？
Or reluctantly accept compliments?
それとも褒め言葉を渋々受け入れますか？
Still don't accept compliments?
まだ褒め言葉を受け入れられないのですか？
It will be all right
大丈夫ですよ
This is to teach foreigners how to speak Chinese
これは外国人に中国語の話し方を教えることです
Then what do we mean by politely accepting compliments?
では、褒め言葉を丁寧に受け入れるとはどういう意味でしょうか？
okay what about this time
よし、今回はどうだろう
a good student
優秀な生徒
Thanks
ありがとう
you are too polite
あなたは礼儀正しすぎます
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
where where
どこだ
I am over-flattered
お世辞すぎる
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
Don't dare not dare
あえてしないでください
Well, this is what he said politely.
そうですね、彼は丁寧にこう言いました。
Four ways to accept compliments
褒め言葉を受け入れる4つの方法
So
それで
shall i use this book first
まずこの本を使ってみようか
OK
OK
suppose i now
私が今だとします
do a single sentence exercise
一文の練習をする
practice a single sentence
一文を練習する
this music is
この音楽は
well this is just now
まあ、これは今だけです
I can choose one of these eight sentences, for example,
たとえば、次の 8 つの文から 1 つを選択できます。
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
did he go in
彼は入りましたか
i didn't open it
私はそれを開けませんでした
ok ok do it again
わかりました、もう一度やりましょう
ok good
いいよ
Again
また
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
what's wrong with this
これの何が問題なのか
He doesn't listen to me today, it's really helpless
今日は彼が私の言うことを聞いてくれない、本当にどうしようもない
Do you want to plug it in or not? Plug it in, right?
差し込みますか?差し込みますか?
Don't plug it in yet, right?
まだ接続してないですよね？
Can't try it, it's already nine o'clock
試してはいけない、もう9時だ
ok ok let's try again
わかりました、もう一度試してみましょう
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
No, one more time
いいえ、もう一度
It's not right now
今はダメだ
You said the mic was too big, my mic is too big
あなたはマイクが大きすぎると言った、私のマイクは大きすぎる
OK
OK
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
You said I'm going to turn this off, right?
これを消すって言ったよね？
Is this the effect?
これが効果なのでしょうか？
in this way
この上
OK
OK
good start
よいスタート
you are such a good student
あなたはとても良い学生です
right
右
ok this time it's ok
よし、今回は大丈夫だ
Okay, he told me this sentence, the total score of what I just said is here
オーケー、彼は私にこの文を言いました、私が今言ったことの合計スコアはここにあります
My four scores are here, for example, the pronunciation is 85 points
私の 4 つのスコアはここにあります。たとえば、発音は 85 点です
We can see why it is 85 points
なぜ85点なのかがわかります
Then you will immediately discover what I just said, this is the pronunciation of each word
そうすれば、私が今言ったことはすぐにわかります。これが各単語の発音です。
All the coiled snakes I deliberately did not coil
とぐろを巻いた蛇はすべて、意図的にとぐろを巻かなかった
So he told me all the curly sounds were wrong
それで彼は私に、巻き舌はすべて間違っていると言った
These snake sounds are wrong. For example, this body only has 50 points.
これらのヘビの鳴き声は間違っています。たとえば、この体のポイントは 50 しかありません。
then this wait wait wait
それからこれは待って待って
So on average I only have 100 points for everything else
つまり、他のものは平均して 100 点しかありません
This is this only 50 points
これだけで50点
So my pronunciation is a total of 85 points
つまり私の発音は合計85点です
So what if I don't know how to pronounce this snake sound?
では、この巻き毛のヘビの音の発音がわからない場合はどうすればよいでしょうか?
i can click
クリックできます
ok listen
わかりました、聞いてください
This is the difference in the poses of my four faculties
これが私の4つの学部の姿勢の違いです
I can also click here
ここをクリックすることもできます
OK I order this
わかりました、これを注文します
He will tell me how to roll when you roll
あなたが転がるとき、彼は私に転がり方を教えてくれるでしょう
It's going to be rolled like this
こんな感じで巻いていきます
etc.
等
OK, so this is 85 points
はい、これで85点です
We see that the pitch is the pitch
ピッチがピッチであることがわかります
Also how does the tone change
また音色はどのように変化しますか
I only have 52 points, what's going on?
52ポイントしかないのですが、どうなっているのでしょうか？
You'll see right away that I pronounced it as a whole on purpose.
私がこれ全体を意図的に発音したことがすぐにわかります。
Turned into a third tone so he told you this isn't right
3番目の音になったので、彼はそれは正しくないと言いました
And then when this becomes the third tone becomes the second tone
そして、これが 3 番目のトーンになると 2 番目のトーンになります
You're all one so this is wrong too
みんなひとつだからこれも間違ってる
Just these two mistakes, so the result becomes only 52 points
この2つのミスだけで52点しか取れない
So what is this timing?
それで、このタイミングは何ですか？
This is the relative relationship between the length of each of my sounds
これは私の各音の長さの相対的な関係です。
How much is it different from the teacher's
先生のとどれくらい違うの？
Then what
じゃあ何
This emphasis is the accent
この強調がアクセントです
That is to say
つまり
every sound of me
私のあらゆる音
the size of the volume
ボリュームのサイズ
How much is it different from the teacher, etc.
先生とどれくらい違うのかなど。
That's how much my total score is
私の合計スコアはこれくらいです
good
良い
so i can do a conversation exercise now
これで会話の練習ができます
Thanks
ありがとう
leave
離れる
you are too polite
あなたは礼儀正しすぎます
thank you for being so kind
とても親切にしていただきありがとうございました
didn't go in
入らなかった
I want
私が欲しい
This is the third demo
これは 3 番目のデモです
I didn't make it but here we go
間に合わなかったけど、行きましょう
I go back to the last
最後に戻ります
We actually did one thing now
私たちは今、実際に一つのことをしました
Another thing I'm actually doing right now is a conversation game
他に今実際にやっていることは会話ゲームです
Because the one just now looked less fun
さっきのはあまり面白くなかったから
So we hope to make a richer dialogue
より豊かな対話をしていきたいと考えています
Let people learn like playing games
ゲームのように学習できるようにする
Because the game is people love to eat
ゲームは食べるのが大好きだから
So
それで
The way we think about it is to put
私たちの考え方としては、
Make a number-like dialogue script
数字のような会話スクリプトを作成する
then every love
それからすべての愛
Let's assume a situation like dining in a restaurant
レストランで食事をするような状況を想定してみましょう
then let this
それならこれにしましょう
Each time there are many sentences to choose from
毎回、たくさんの文から選択できます
Then choose along the way
あとは途中で選ぶ
different roads get different paths
異なる道には異なる道が得られる
the practice times of pronunciation unit
発音単元の練習時間
all different
全部違う
So the things a computer can do
それで、コンピュータができることは、
It is to replace users online at any time
オンラインでいつでもユーザーを入れ替えることができます
choose the best path
最善の道を選ぶ
Wherever you say something bad
どこで悪口を言っても
We'll try to make it as fast as possible
できるだけ早くできるよう努めます
the most times, let it train well
ほとんどの場合、よく訓練しましょう
For example, it doesn't roll its tongue
たとえば、舌を巻きません。
I just give it a lot of retroflex
私はそれにたくさんのレトロフレックスを与えます
Let it roll like hell, wait
地獄のように転がらせて、待ってください
i can say something different
違うことも言えるよ
to practice the same sound
同じ音を練習する
Instead of practicing the same sentence over and over
同じ文を何度も練習するのではなく
Because we are going to practice repeatedly
繰り返し練習するので
that good student good student
あの良い生徒 良い生徒
I can now stop repeating
これで繰り返すのをやめることができます
I can use different in the dialog
ダイアログで別のものを使用できます
practice repeatedly
繰り返し練習する
Haven't learned the pronunciation unit yet
発音の単元をまだ学習していない
so i can show up early now
だから今は早めに到着できるよ
Learn all the pronunciation units well in a short period of time
短期間ですべての発音単元をしっかり学習
For example
例えば
This is the waiting and ordering part
これは待機と注文の部分です
This one tries to say welcome, etc.
これは、ようこそなどと言おうとします。
Is there any place?
どこかありますか？
you can say yes or no
あなたは「はい」または「いいえ」を言うことができます
what if there is
あるとしたらどうしますか
If not, how can we wait
そうでない場合、どうやって待つことができますか?
So this is a vertical structure
つまりこれは垂直構造です
what about us
私たちについてはどうですか
has a long dialogue script
長い会話スクリプトがある
Start with a phone call
まずは電話から
Ordering, positioning, asking for directions until waiting for the table to order and serve
テーブルの注文と提供を待つまでの注文、位置決め、道順の確認
until the farewell
別れまで
you can go back
戻ってもいいよ
because after you turn around
なぜならあなたが振り向いた後だから
You have to eat the next meal after eating
食べたら次の食事を食べなければなりません
keep eating with different people
食事を続けるためにさまざまな人との約束をする
Then every road can be different
そうすれば、すべての道は異なるものになる可能性があります
So if this tongue roll won't roll
だからこの舌巻きが転がらないなら
Just let it roll down and wait
ただ転がして待ってください
Ok, that's all for today
さて、今日はこれで終わりです
One last word
最後に一言
open sesame
開けゴマ
This is an allusion to Alibaba
これはアリババをほのめかしたものです
you guys know what it means to say
あなたたちはそれが何を意味するか知っていますか
just talk
ちょうど話
The door that can open the treasure
宝物を開ける扉
this is human
これは人間です
man's dream since time immemorial
太古の昔からの人類の夢
So what we're going to talk about today is actually
それで、今日私たちが話そうとしていることは、実際には
The Internet is the single most important treasure trove of knowledge in the future
インターネットは将来において最も重要な知識の宝庫です
And the time to open the door to the treasure of knowledge with sound
そして音で知の宝庫への扉を開く時が来た
is getting closer
近づいています
Of course many people will ask
もちろん多くの人が尋ねます
You use a machine to recognize life
あなたは生命を認識するために機械を使います
So what
だから何
At best it is the same as the human ear
せいぜい人間の耳と同じです
In fact, you still have so many mistakes today
実際のところ、今日もまだたくさんの間違いがあります
Can't compare with human ear
人間の耳とは比較にならない
But it does not matter
しかし、それは問題ではありません
Because machines can process huge amounts of information
機械は膨大な量の情報を処理できるため、
But the machine can repeat
しかし、機械は繰り返すことができます
Repeat service anytime, anywhere
いつでもどこでもサービスを繰り返します
These two points are the machine native human
この2点は機械本来の人間です
so what we have to do
それで私たちがしなければならないこと
is how to take advantage of these strengths of the machine
機械のこれらの強みをどのように活用するかです
Well though it has a place
まぁ場所はあるけどね
not so good
あまりよくない
Should be pretty good too
もかなり良いはずです
ok i want to end my speech today
さて、今日のスピーチを終わりにしたいと思います
thank you
ありがとう
Okay, thank you, Mr. Li, for your wonderful speech.
さて、リーさん、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。
Although we have two full hours
たっぷり2時間あるのに
Let's discuss Q&A in about 10 minutes
10分程度で質疑応答を行います
Do you have any questions?
何か質問がありますか？
please
お願いします
Teacher, is this part of AI?
先生、これはAIの一部ですか？
You can ask the microphone
マイクに質問することができます
OK
OK
This is part of AI
これはAIの一部です
does it count
それはカウントされますか
Does it count as part of the AI?
AIの一部としてカウントされますか?
It actually depends on how AI people define AI
実際には、AI が AI をどのように定義するかによって異なります。
sure
もちろん
But some people define the AI ​​key very
しかし、一部の人は AI キーを非常に定義しています
Narrow's words
ナローの言葉
Maybe he said it doesn't count
たぶん彼はそれはカウントされないと言ったのでしょう
I think this is fine
これでいいと思います
Depends on see
参照に応じて
That should make it very clear what I'm talking about here.
そうすれば、私がここで何を言っているのかが非常に明確になるはずです。
is the signal with this voice
この声の合図です
Then I use a lot of math and a lot of programming
それから私はたくさんの数学とたくさんのプログラミングを使います
find a way to do it
それを行う方法を見つける
All the things audio signals can do
オーディオ信号でできるすべてのこと
Then it is very clear that the definition is like this
したがって、定義が次のようであることは非常に明らかです
Then the AI ​​person wants to say whether he is AI or not
するとAIの人は自分がAIであるかどうかを言いたいのです
I think it's all right
大丈夫だと思います
OK
OK
good
良い
please teach me
教えて下さい
that today's report was wonderful
今日のレポートは素晴らしかったと
Thanks
ありがとう
There is still an application to the theory of this congressman's identification
この議員の身元特定理論にはまだ応用が残っている
But the current MPs recognize
しかし、現在の国会議員は認識しています
As if this is still not so tomorrow
まるで明日もそうでないかのように
what is the most important bottleneck
最も重要なボトルネックは何ですか
For example, you say that sesame seeds open the door
たとえば、ゴマが扉を開けるって言うけど
But the flower sound of the sesame opening door is not accurate
でもゴマがドアを開ける花の音は正確ではない
Many flower sounds are inaccurate
多くの花の音は不正確です
it won't open the door
それはドアが開きません
Does this technically include software?
これには技術的にソフトウェアが含まれますか?
Is it possible to solve this problem already?
この問題をすでに解決することは可能ですか?
Can make it more general and friendly
より一般的でフレンドリーなものにすることができます
Or are you suggesting that everyone go to the cloud for coordination?
それとも調整のために全員がクラウドに移行することを提案していますか?
Otherwise, there is no way for this congressman to identify
そうでなければ、この議員が特定する方法はありません
Thanks
ありがとう
i want to make a point first
最初に指摘しておきたいのですが
It's just that you found out that something doesn't work
何かがうまくいかないことがわかっただけです
It's not that my pronunciation is bad
私の発音が悪いわけではありません
but a matter of contact
でも連絡事項
Or the problem that the signal is not coming in
または信号が入っていないという問題
It's just that he can't recognize it himself
それは彼自身が認識できないだけです
the same
同じ
This is about different accents for different people
これは人によって異なるアクセントについてです
all these decades
この数十年ずっと
Many people have done various researches
多くの人がさまざまな研究を行っています
there are many ways to handle this
これに対処する方法はたくさんあります
Then you can also understand today
そうすれば今日も分かるよ
There are indeed some systems that do a good job
確かに良い仕事をするシステムがいくつかあります
For example, there are some good features on mobile phones
たとえば、携帯電話にはいくつかの優れた機能があります
Then he is indeed working with different people
それから彼は実際にさまざまな人たちと仕事をしています
That means that in fact this
ということは、実はこれは
adapt to different
異なるものに適応する
of different voices
さまざまな声の
different accent thing
アクセントが違うもの
In fact, there are already quite good solutions
実際、すでに非常に優れたソリューションがあります
That's got pretty good results.
それはかなり良い結果が出ています。
only limited time today
今日だけの時間限定
I can't have this
これは手に入らない
too much time
時間が多すぎる
no way to talk
話す方法がない
There are so many ideas to do this
これを実現するためのアイデアはたくさんあります
There are many effective ways
効果的な方法はたくさんあります
Allows different accents to be handled
さまざまなアクセントを処理できるようにします
So many systems today
今日では非常に多くのシステムが
You can see that they are all speaker independent
すべてスピーカーに依存していないことがわかります。
He can listen to what different people are saying
彼はさまざまな人の言うことを聞くことができる
This should not be the main obstacle
これが主な障害ではないはずです
But the main obstacle should be to say
しかし、主な障害は次のとおりです。
Speech recognition will never be 100% correct
音声認識が 100% 正確であることはありません
always have a lot of mistakes
いつも間違いが多い
We must live with those mistakes
私たちはそれらの間違いとともに生きなければなりません
All the applications I just talked about
今話したすべてのアプリケーション
In fact, they are all live with those mistakes
実際、彼らは皆、そうした間違いを抱えて生きているのです
For example
例えば
when i do a summary
まとめをするときに
I obviously let there be a typo in it, it doesn't matter
明らかにタイプミスがありましたが、それは問題ではありません
Because as long as I get enough of it right
なぜなら、私が正しく十分に理解している限り
i know what their point is
彼らの言いたいことはわかっています
I'll just grab it
ただ掴みます
it's okay to be wrong
間違っても大丈夫です
I'm looking for the same thing
同じものを探しています
if i'm looking for this
これを探しているなら
That is, I can't be right about everything.
つまり、私はすべてについて正しいことはできません。
But as long as I catch his stuff
しかし、私が彼のものをキャッチしている限り
So all of our applications today are in this category
したがって、今日のアプリケーションはすべてこのカテゴリに属します
Like if you have some product on your phone
携帯電話に何らかの製品がある場合のように
it can answer your questions
あなたの質問に答えることができます
also the same
また同じです
It is actually able to identify the inside
実は内部を特定できる
important key to your important problem
あなたの重要な問題への重要な鍵
it caught
捕まった
It just knows how to answer
それはただ答え方を知っているだけだ
Basically we all think in this direction
基本的に私たちは皆この方向で考えています
The real state today should be what I just said
今日の本当の状態は私が今言ったとおりであるはずです
We can't be 100% right
私たちは100％正しいことはできません
The situation will be different if the judgment is different
判断が違えば状況も変わる
if you talk on the street
路上で話したら
This one has a lot of background noise
これにはバックグラウンドノイズがたくさんあります
If I'm chatting with someone else
他の人とチャットしている場合
So what this says
それで、これが何を言っているのか
It's not the same as the usual pronunciation, etc.
通常の発音などとは異なります。
will change
変更されます
That's why my error always happens
それが私のエラーがいつも起こる理由です
This may be the biggest problem right now
これが今の最大の問題かもしれない
good
良い
yes
はい
you have to click
クリックする必要があります
Excuse me Mr. Li
すみません、李さん
then in the western language
それから西洋語で
They are phonetic characters
表音文字です
Are there fewer obstacles in this regard?
この点に関して障害は少ないでしょうか？
if it is like this
このような場合
If we can make Chinese also
中国語も入れられれば
Pinyin as much as possible
可能な限りピンイン
Can this obstacle be broken?
この障害物は突破できるでしょうか？
Although some of this is pinyin
一部ピンインですが
some are some this block
このブロックの一部は
But judging by the sound signal
しかし、音声信号から判断すると、
they look alike
それらは似ている
pretty much the same thing
ほぼ同じこと
It's just that when I render with text
それは、テキストでレンダリングするときだけです
What kind of text is used to present
どのようなテキストを使用してプレゼンテーションを行うか
Then of course when this text appears
もちろん、このテキストが表示されたときは
its structure is different
その構造は異なります
from this point of view
この観点から
We feel that doing Chinese is the same as doing English
私たちは中国語をやるのは英語をやるのと同じだと感じています
almost the same difficulty
ほぼ同じ難易度
Then each has its own difficulties
それからそれぞれに独自の困難があります
Chinese has a lot of difficulties
中国語は難しいことが多い
just said
今言いました
English also has a lot of difficulties
英語も難しいことが多い
Today's Possible English Recognition
今日の可能な英語認識
better effect
より良い効果
That's because many people do it
それは多くの人がやっているからです
Then make great efforts
じゃあ頑張ってね
The data they collect is much
彼らが収集するデータは膨大です
they use more
彼らはより多くの量を使用します
say thousands of hours
何千時間も言う
Tens of thousands of hours of data
数万時間のデータ
Thousands of computers connected to run
数千台のコンピュータが接続されて実行される
then they can do better
そうすれば彼らはもっとうまくやれるだろう
In fact, we feel
実際、私たちは感じています
The real difficulty is close
本当の困難はすぐそこにある
Then all the problems are also close
そうすればすべての問題も解決します
just different
ただ違うだけ
In fact, Chinese is also spelled out with a bunch of sounds.
実際、中国語もたくさんの音で表記されます。
not much different from English
英語とあまり変わらない
If we look at it from the level of sound
音のレベルで見ると
The difference lies in the presentation of the text
違いはテキストの表示にあります
Of course, the text rendering is different and has a great impact
もちろん、テキストのレンダリングも異なり、大きな影響を与えます
Because I'm going to use those words to help me train
その言葉を使ってトレーニングするから
So why?
なぜ？
For example, speaking Chinese because it is a square character
たとえば、四角い文字なので中国語を話します。
So when I use text to render
したがって、テキストを使用してレンダリングするときは、
For example, a lot of words have the same pronunciation
たとえば、同じ発音の単語がたくさんあります。
So what are these issues that are different
では、これらの異なる問題は何ですか
So if the computer's CPU speeds up
つまり、コンピュータのCPUが高速化すると、
will it be better
良くなるでしょうか
all of course
もちろんすべて
Today's speech technology has not reached any stage
今日の音声テクノロジーはまだどの段階にも入っていません
You can buy pretty good voice systems on the street
かなり優れた音声システムが路上で購入できます
Do it all on your phone
すべてを携帯電話で行う
how do those
それらはどうやって
it uses a very large amount
非常に大量に使用します
Mobile phone has a lot of data
携帯電話には大量のデータが入っています
And a very large amount of calculations to train it and so on
そしてそれを訓練するための非常に大量の計算など
Of course you're not pretending over there
もちろん、そこではふりをしているわけではありません
Those are not all things installed in the phone
電話機にインストールされているものはそれだけではありません
The answer to your question is in the cloud
あなたの質問への答えはクラウドにあります
that is to say
つまり
Today's Today's Today's Cloud Technology
今日の今日の今日のクラウドテクノロジー
can't get to this stage
この段階に到達できない
not the same as 20 years ago
20年前と同じではない
Of course technology has improved a lot
もちろん技術はかなり進歩しています
It is also important because
それも重要なので、
This computer is much faster
このコンピュータははるかに高速です
a lot more data
より多くのデータ
People put in a lot more effort
人々はさらに多くの努力をする
these things add up
これらのことを合計すると
Of course there are new technologies
もちろん新しい技術もある
All of these have effects
これらすべてに効果があります
Thanks
ありがとう
two thousand
二千
Hello Mr. Li
こんにちは、リーさん
You spoke very well today
今日はとても上手に話せましたね
I want to say that there is a commercial problem.
商業的に問題があると言いたいのです。
It is about after the model is built
モデルを構築した後の話です
Then this Chinese is actually Chinese
じゃあこの中国人は実は中国人だ
A high percentage of the world
世界の高い割合
If htc these are combined with this
htc の場合、これらをこれと組み合わせると
There is a part about intelligent property
知的財産に関する部分があります
put it some
それを少し置いてください
Because many models
モデルが多いので
not a system
システムではありません
If becomes a structure
構造物になれば
Then talk to the phone for advice
それから電話で相談してください
Combined with this, it looks like Samsung has mobile phones that use Chinese.
これを組み合わせると、サムスンは中国語を使用する携帯電話を持っているようです。
he stands here
彼はここに立っている
In fact, we can do a market share. Do you have the idea to share all these
実際、私たちはマーケットシェアをすることができます。これらすべてをシェアするという考えはありますか?
no number i know
私が知っている番号はありません
The foreign series are also developing well
海外シリーズも順調に展開中
Some of the rooms in Taiwan are for tourism
台湾の部屋の一部は観光用です
It does a good job on mobile as well. Some wins
モバイルでも優れたパフォーマンスを発揮します。
Is there anything in this plan because National Taiwan University is quite ahead?
国立台湾大学がかなり進んでいるということで、この計画には何かあるのでしょうか？
Make this market a share to balance in the mobile phone
この市場を携帯電話でバランスのとれたシェアにする
Competitors above are able to cut a piece out here is one of mine
上の競合他社は、ここで私の作品を切り出すことができます。
I don't know what to think, no one will go this way
何を考えればいいのか分からない、誰もここには行かないだろう
Taiwan University doesn't have the same idea, thank you
台湾大学は同じ考えを持っていません、ありがとう
i think it's a good idea
良いアイデアだと思います
But someone needs to do these things
しかし、誰かがこれらのことを行う必要があります
Our technology at Taiwan University is very advanced, but
台湾大学の技術は非常に進んでいますが、
I can't do so many things by myself
私一人ではそんなに多くのことはできません
What I can do is to lead students to make friends with customers and do our research well.
私にできることは、学生がお客様と仲良くなったり、リサーチがうまくできるよう指導することです。
I'm already passed out from this so I'm unlikely to bother with anything else.
私はすでにこのことに気を失っているので、他のことを気にするつもりはありません。
what about the same
同じことはどうですか
Certainly a very large market
確かに非常に大きな市場です
Then you also understand
それならあなたも分かりますよ
For example
例えば
Voice teams around the world today
現在、世界中の音声チーム
all in Chinese
全部中国語で
It is not only our Chinese-speaking world
それは私たちの中国語圏だけではありません
only do Chinese
中国語だけやる
This one in North America, this one in Western Europe
こちらは北米、こちらは西ヨーロッパ
including east asia
東アジアも含めて
Everyone speaks Chinese
みんな中国語を話します
you may know
あなたは知っているかもしれません
Department of Defense of the United States
米国国防総省
they invested a lot of money
彼らは多額の資金を投資した
Buy thousands of computers for others
他人のために数千台のコンピュータを購入する
Do a very good voice system
非常に優れた音声システムを実行する
it has two specified languages
指定された言語が 2 つあります
the first is arabic
一つ目はアラビア語です
The second is Chinese
2人目は中国人です
This is a global program of the U.S. Department of Defense
これは米国国防総省の世界的なプログラムです
you know why very clearly
あなたはその理由をはっきりと知っています
US Department of Defense looks
米国国防総省の見方
its two enemies
その二人の敵
the first is arabic
一つ目はアラビア語です
The second is the person who speaks Chinese
2人目は中国語を話す人です
so do chinese
中国人もそうだよ
In fact, it is very common today
実際、今日ではそれが非常に一般的です
then really have the most resources
その場合、実際に最も多くのリソースを持っています
Can do the best Chinese
最高の中国語ができる
That's actually a lot of teams around the world
実際、世界中にはたくさんのチームがいます
Then we in Taiwan can
そうすれば、台湾にいる私たちは、
the Chinese part
中国の部分
we are technically
私たちは技術的には
Conceptually
概念的には
Definitely leading
間違いなく主導権を握る
but our resources
しかし私たちのリソース
what can be done
何ができるか
is now relatively limited
現在は比較的制限されています
of course
もちろん
If there is an industry
産業があれば
want to do something
何かしたい
I think there is a chance
チャンスはあると思う
Someone needs to think about this
誰かがこれについて考える必要がある
Someone come to organize
誰か整理しに来てね
At this stage, it should be said that there is no
現段階では存在しないと言うべきだろう
sorry about that
それについては申し訳ありません
this may disappoint you
これはあなたを失望させるかもしれません
that last question
最後の質問
I am Zhu Hongyan from the Institute of Modern History
私は近代史研究所の朱紅燕です。
Just mentioned the American text
先ほどアメリカのテキストについて言及しました
I didn't want to mention it
言及したくなかった
But it's basically Sanmou Huntington
でも基本的にはサンモウ・ハンティントンだよ
His Crash of Civilizations
他的Crash of Civilizations
It basically assumes that these two
基本的にはこの２つであると考えられます
Democracy has the biggest impact on America
民主主義はアメリカに最大の影響を与える
Crash may have generated
クラッシュが発生した可能性があります
He originally predicted that China
彼は当初、中国が
later became the number one in the Arab world
後にアラブ世界でナンバーワンになった
He actually wanted the order reversed.
彼は実際には順序を逆にしたかったのです。
Then the question I want to ask is not this
それでは、私が聞きたい質問はこれではありません
I feel very close
とても親近感を感じます
because it's very hard
とても難しいから
very difficult
非常に難しい
so if it was me
それで私だったら
i really can't do it
本当にできない
Then what I'm thinking is the other side
それで私が考えているのは向こう側です
is what you just mentioned
それはあなたが今言ったことです
is literal language
文字通りの言語です
seems to be text lead
テキストリードのようです
language is built on words
言語は言葉の上に成り立っています
and then to operate
そして操作するために
if it is like this
このような場合
How to communicate with the whole system of book classification
書籍分類システム全体と通信する方法
all the key is
すべての鍵は
Will it be faster to combine with book classification
書籍分類と組み合わせた方が早いでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
we didn't think about it
私たちはそれについて考えませんでした
for us
わたしたちのため
language is language
言語は言語だ
languages ​​come in different forms
言語にはさまざまな形があります
then the sound is
そのときの音は
We are called spoken language
私たちは話し言葉と呼ばれます
is spoken language
話し言葉です
The text is written language
文章は書き言葉です
is written language
書き言葉です
Then if it prints out
それが印刷された場合
princess language
プリンセス言語
printed language
印刷言語
of course
もちろん
Operation still needs to be done through text
操作は依然としてテキストで行う必要があります
Then your operation must be through the text
その場合、操作はテキストを通じて行う必要があります。
Text is the basis of language
文字は言語の基礎です
in today's case
今日の場合
because we have to use these words
これらの言葉を使わなければならないからです
or its phonetic symbols to mark these sounds
またはその発音記号でこれらの音をマークします
know what it is
それが何であるかを知っています
what is it
それは何ですか
but the other way around
しかしその逆
we can also imagine
私たちも想像することができます
Actually this has some
実はこれにはいくつかの特徴があります
many languages ​​in the world
世界中の多くの言語
it has no text at all
テキストがまったくありません
It can also exist directly
直接存在することもできます
Or rather it has only very simple
というか、非常にシンプルなものしかありません
some first blood symbols
いくつかの最初の血のシンボル
its language exists
その言語は存在する
So from that point of view
ですから、その観点からすると
Sound may be something that appeared earlier than words
音は言葉よりも先に現れたものなのかもしれない
Said the operation is not working
操作がうまくいかないと言われました
sound does not work
音が鳴らない
or through text
またはテキストを通じて
It seems that our current experience is indeed the case
私たちの現在の経験は確かに当てはまるようです
That is to say, your voice must
つまり、あなたの声は、
label it to some extent
ある程度ラベルを付ける
Then I was able to do many things
そしたら色々な事が出来るようになった
So that target can be text
そのターゲットをテキストにすることができます
can be phonetic
発音的なものになる可能性があります
can be e.g. letters
文字などにすることができます
different situations have different situations
状況が異なれば状況も異なります
Then in our Chinese we speak square characters
それから私たちの中国語では四角い文字を話します
Western languages ​​have pinyin characters, which is the method of marking, etc.
西洋言語にはピンインという文字があり、それによる採点方法などが挙げられます。
so it's a complicated thing
それは複雑なことだ
Different language situations are different
言語環境が異なれば状況も異なります
So actually in the field of phonetics
実際に音声学の分野では
Almost every language we have has its own
私たちが持つほぼすべての言語には独自の言語があります
A whole bunch of teams working on their languages
たくさんのチームがそれぞれの言語に取り組んでいます
This is to do a good job of language today, at least eighty or ninety
これは、今日、少なくとも 80 か 90 の言語をうまくやるということです。
You are also kissing me teacher ask for advice
あなたも私にキスしてます、先生、アドバイスをお願いします
can i ask a question
質問してもいいですか
That is to say, we are currently saying
つまり、現在私たちが言っているのは、
Let's say we're talking on the phone
電話で話しているとしましょう
it can show text
テキストを表示できます
Will the field improve in the future?
その後、フィールドは改善されますか?
We use human voice to speak to our mobile phones
私たちは人間の声を使って携帯電話に話しかけます
The mobile phone can also answer us with voice
携帯電話でも音声で応答できます
Thanks
ありがとう
this is of course possible
これはもちろん可能です
There should be some systems that do these things now
現在、これらのことを行うシステムがいくつかあるはずです
because basically
なぜなら基本的に
It's easier for machines to talk
機械が話すほうが簡単だ
because it only needs to say one sentence
一文だけ言えばいいので
Just let others understand
他の人に理解してもらいましょう
But you have to identify what this sentence is
しかし、この文が何であるかを特定する必要があります
is much harder
はるかに難しい
Because that sentence can say thousands of ways
なぜならその文は何千もの言い方ができるからです
So in fact, we actually have a lot of
実際、私たちは実際にたくさんのものを持っています
e.g. dialogue system
例: 対話システム
It's all machines talking to people
それはすべて機械が人々と話しているだけです
Even in the country, there are actually many
国内でも実はたくさんあるんですよ
You may not have noticed
気づいていないかもしれません
Sometimes, for example, the bank makes a phone call to say
たとえば、銀行から電話がかかることがあります。
what about your credit card
あなたのクレジットカードはどうですか
or something
か何か
Or what the election caller said
あるいは選挙の電話をかけてきた人が言ったこと
what happened to which candidate
どの候補者に何が起こったのか
He also said a few words to you
彼もあなたにいくつかの言葉を言いました
you thought he was real
あなたは彼が本物だと思った
Actually he is a machine
実は彼は機械なのです
This actually exists
これは実際に存在します
that sort of thing exists
そういうものは存在する
That is to say, will it progress to the point of generalization in the future?
つまり、今後一般化まで進むのでしょうか？
Universalization should not be a technical issue
汎用化は技術的な問題であってはなりません
It's about having someone with the power of this business
このビジネスの力を持った人がいることです
to drive him
彼を運転するために
Let him really have enough people to do these things
これらのことを行うのに十分な人材を彼に確保させてください
that should be a chance
それはチャンスであるはずだ
Well, that's because of time
まあ、それは時間のせいです
We thank you all for your participation
ご参加いただきありがとうございました
Thank you Professor Li Ningshan for your wonderful speech
李寧山教授、素晴らしい講演をありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
ok thank you thank you
わかりました、ありがとう、ありがとう